<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 12:59:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate on a Lookup in SSRS</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2014-11-23-aggregate-on-a-lookup-in-ssrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 12:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2014-11-23-aggregate-on-a-lookup-in-ssrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-what&#34;&gt;The What&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to join multiple datasets inside SSRS, perhaps because of different sources, grains of detail etc, then you often need to aggregate over both datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In SSRS, you can easily perform aggregations over another dataset but it can be tough to do this based on a grouping factor in your main dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key example of this might be Sales and Purchases &amp;#8211; you want to show both of these by month but they come from two different data sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could build two tables that appear to be just one table but this can be really clunky. Instead, you want just one table with the month, the total sales, and the total purchases in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there&amp;#8217;s no tidy way of doing this built in, you have the power to add your own functions to SSRS using the Code window of the report&amp;#8217;s properties. Provided here is a block of VB script that can be added to your SSRS report to allow you to do those tricky aggregations as if they were just another built in function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call it AggLookup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>