<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Censornet on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/censornet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Censornet on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 07:46:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/censornet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor update to HIBPwned</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2017-05-05-minor-update-hibpwned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 07:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2017-05-05-minor-update-hibpwned/</guid>
      <description>A new version of HIBPwned has been accepted onto CRAN. This occurred yesterday so it could still be filtering into some mirrors.
HIBPwned is an R wrapper for the useful website HaveIBeenPwned and if you don&amp;#8217;t already utilise the package or the site &amp;#8211; you should. HaveIBeenPwned tells you when your details are included in data breaches. This is vital information to get quickly as it means you can sooner protect yourself from people trying to use the breach information to break into your accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIBPwned on CRAN</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-06-09-hibpwned-on-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 08:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-06-09-hibpwned-on-cran/</guid>
      <description>Part of my (slowly) working pipeline of coding projects has been an R package that wraps the fantastic HaveIBeenPwned.com API.
If you&amp;#8217;re not already familiar with HaveIBeenPwned, rectify the situation, NOW! Don&amp;#8217;t worry about continuing to read the rest of the post; getting yourself signed up for account breach notifications is way more important!Go now!
/giphy run
With that stern admonishment out of the way&amp;#8230;
HIBPwned is a feature complete R package that allows you to use every (currently) available endpoint of the API.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>