<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presenting on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/tags/presenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presenting on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:27:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itsalocke.com/blog/tags/presenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Data Science activities in London, June 27th – 29th</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/r-and-data-science-activities-in-london-june-27th--29th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/r-and-data-science-activities-in-london-june-27th--29th/</guid>
      <description>Locke Data will be up to some shenanigans of various stripes in the big smoke. We hope to see you at some of them!
June 26th &amp;#8212; Monday Introduction to R (Newcastle) I won&amp;#8217;t be in London for this but I&amp;#8217;ll be doing a day of Introduction to R in Newcastle. This is supporting the local user groups and costs up to £90 for the whole day.Intro to R in Newcastle, June 26th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community workshops</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/community-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/community-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Following on from when we announced the availability of our community workshops, we&amp;#8217;ve got three in the next three months that folks can attend.
May 19th &amp;#8211; Data science project in a day We&amp;#8217;ll be in Kiev, Ukraine, doing a whole data science project in a day. This is intended to give people a little bit of code, process, and critical thinking along the whole data science workflow. This will enable folks to see how it hangs together and decide where and how much they want to invest their learning in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing community R workshops</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/announcing-community-r-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/announcing-community-r-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of why I&amp;#8217;ve launched Locke Data is so that I can give back more to my communities. I want to give more time and more support to others. One of the first steps is doing some activities that give financial support to community groups without damaging my startup cashflow! Community R workshops that fund local user groups is the first activity I&amp;#8217;ll be trialling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s involved, and what you might want to consider if you&amp;#8217;d like to be a part of this endeavour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note to (potential) new speakers: It’s ok not to be perfect!</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/a-note-to-potential-new-speakers-its-ok-not-to-be-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 10:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/a-note-to-potential-new-speakers-its-ok-not-to-be-perfect/</guid>
      <description>This is a T-SQL Tuesday Post in response to Andy Bek&amp;#8217;s kick off about growing new speakers. You can write your own advice for new speakers, or blog your journey to speaking.
 I&amp;#8217;m always trying to encourage new speakers and the biggest fear I hear is &amp;#8220;I won&amp;#8217;t be any good at it&amp;#8221;. Well, you won&amp;#8217;t be perfect at it, that&amp;#8217;s for sure. You may start off really bad at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for (lightning) talks</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/ideas-for-lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/ideas-for-lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m trying to encourage more lightning talks at my user groups, and I started by writing a plea to folks at my local R user group, caRdiff. In it I included some ideas for lightning talks, and of course, these can be used as the basis for long talks too. We had some fun batting this list around and expanding it in the Cardiff dev group. I thought it was worth sharing, and getting some more ideas from you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not an expert</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/not-an-expert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 08:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/not-an-expert/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t think of myself as an expert because an expert is someone with very deep knowledge of a comparatively narrow field.
For better or worse, a lot of my sense of satisfaction with life derives from throwing myself into some enterprise that I don&amp;#8217;t have the people skills, the knowledge, and/or the resources for succeeding. I welcome the failures, the dead ends, the crises of faith, because if it wasn&amp;#8217;t hard it wouldn&amp;#8217;t be worth doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PASS Summit2016 submissions feedback</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/my-pass-summit2016-submissions-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 11:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/my-pass-summit2016-submissions-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really liked the way Brent showed us &lt;a href=&#34;https://ozar.me/2016/06/feedback-on-my-sqlpass-summit16-abstract-submissions/&#34;&gt;his feedback received&lt;/a&gt; and since mimicry is the best form of flattery, I thought I&amp;#8217;d go ahead and do it too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t get any accepted abstracts, and I&amp;#8217;m actually grateful. The recent stresses to do with the PASS dramas aside, I would have had to use 5 days holiday time, pay for flights and hotel, and then flown out a week later for MVP Summit. Now I can attend some other conferences and/or have a Christmas break! Woo hoo 😀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming R for Microsoft training days</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/upcoming-r-for-microsoft-training-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 09:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/upcoming-r-for-microsoft-training-days/</guid>
      <description>In May, I will be delivering two R for Microsoft training days. These two days will focus on some R fundamentals and applying these fundamentals within the Microsoft Data Platform. These training days are ideal if you know one half of the components &amp;#8211; whether that&amp;#8217;s the R bit or the Microsoft BI bit. Either way, you&amp;#8217;ll learn about the other half.
SQLBits SQLBits XV is being held in Liverpool this year and my training day is on May 4th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should presenters have to pay to attend?</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/should-presenters-have-to-pay-to-attend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/should-presenters-have-to-pay-to-attend/</guid>
      <description>I recently did something for the first time: I declined to speak somewhere. It was never stated on the submission page, and was raised only after my session was accepted &amp;#8211; they wanted me to buy a ticket to attend and I refused&amp;nbsp;to do that.
As a speaker I love donating my time and I really don&amp;#8217;t mind paying my own&amp;nbsp;Travel and Expenses (T&amp;amp;E) but to have to pay to get in the door of the place I&amp;#8217;m speaking at feels wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boris’ presentation agency – 356labs</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/boris-presentation-agency--356labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 09:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/boris-presentation-agency--356labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://borishristov.com/&#34;&gt;Boris Hristrov&lt;/a&gt;, Data Platform MVP, design whizz, and all-round great guy, recently launched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.356labs.com/&#34;&gt;356labs&lt;/a&gt;. Boris wrote a great &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluralsight.com/courses/presentation-design-introduction&#34;&gt;Presentation Design course&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://preview.pluralsight.com/&#34;&gt;PluralSight&lt;/a&gt;, you can sign up for a trial of PluralSight and watch the course if you&amp;#8217;d like to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an avid reader of design stuff I did find I knew some of the things on the course, but the context and application were very helpful. Off the back of his course, I went on to produce my most visually impressive presentation slide deck to date &amp;#8211; Agile BI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look over his site and asked a few questions since I was really curious. Here are the responses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women doing technology</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/women-doing-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/women-doing-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, another Women in Technology conference got forwarded around and looking at the agenda, I snapped. I asked to not see any more goddamn WiT conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really fed up with women talking about being in tech. I don&amp;#8217;t perceive any value in attending a conference dedicated to that. I want to see more women talking about doing tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom LaTeX Beamer style templates for rmarkdown</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/custom-latex-beamer-style-templates-for-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/custom-latex-beamer-style-templates-for-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been producing presentations via R using &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and outputting to either ioslides or slidify. That was excellent, because I could provide a CSS that customised the look and feel (relatively) easily*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I wanted to produce a PDF version, I couldn&amp;#8217;t make ones that look as good as the pure LaTeX versions I could make on &lt;a href=&#34;http://overleaf.com&#34;&gt;overleaf.com&lt;/a&gt;. So I started RTFMing when I wanted to replicate the look and feel from my presentation, The LaTeX Show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t want to spend a huge amount of time on it, so this little story of hack and slash may feel a bit dirty to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many is too many conferences?</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/how-many-is-too-many-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 17:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/how-many-is-too-many-conferences/</guid>
      <description>The SQL Server community has a lot of events. In the UK alone this year we will have/had in 2015:
 more than 75 user group meetings 5 SQL Saturdays 8 days of Relay 1 SQL in the City 3 to 5 days of SQLBits possibly a SQL Santa and probably more that I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten or not know about at the time of writing this  You could attend 2 days of conference per month (cpm from now on) on average in the UK alone, just at dedicated SQL events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Portugal</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/sqlsaturday-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 09:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/sqlsaturday-portugal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlsaturday.com/369/EventHome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Portugal 2015&lt;/a&gt; has been a huge amount of fun but I&amp;#8217;ve also learnt a lot. A big thank you to the organisers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are my slides and notes from sessions I attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-bi&#34;&gt;Agile BI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My session slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Saturday Exeter: Steph &amp; Oz’s slides</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/sql-saturday-exeter-steph--ozs-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 16:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/sql-saturday-exeter-steph--ozs-slides/</guid>
      <description>Well SQL Saturday Exeter flew by. T&amp;#8217;was great catching up with people, seeing folks learn how to use (old &amp;amp; new) tools better, and just generally watching everyone having a great time at one of the best organised conferences I have the pleasure of going to.
Here are links to all the slide decks etc that we presented this weekend:
 My R: analysis to integration training day notes &amp;amp; source code My agile BI slide deck My Shiny: dashboards in R slide deck &amp;amp; source code Oz&amp;#8217;s SSRS: Beyond the basics slide deck &amp;amp; source code  If you attended any of our sessions, give us some constructive criticism!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unified.Diff: source control smells &amp; LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/unified.diff-source-control-smells--latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/unified.diff-source-control-smells--latex/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of presenting at unified.diff, a general programming user group in Cardiff, last night and was able to debut my LaTeX show!
If you&amp;#8217;d like to talk at the group about anything tech related tweet them on @unifiedDiff. They&amp;#8217;re very flexible on time and topic so if you&amp;#8217;re based in Cardiff or are coming down to see a client, it&amp;#8217;s an easy way of delivering a talk and meeting some nice people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – improving font sizes</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--improving-font-sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 12:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--improving-font-sizes/</guid>
      <description>A recurring problem with my presentations is font size.
 The inclusion of code in my Rmarkdown slides was by default too small. Upping the fontsize via CSS worked ok, but when I switched to a shiny app version for my intro to shiny, it reverted and I&amp;#8217;m afraid to say I didn&amp;#8217;t notice beforehand. I use PuTTY for showing how to do some stuff in the linux command line but the font&amp;#8217;s quite small by default and Gail Shaw&amp;#8217;s tip of Magnifier in my session was tough to use I&amp;#8217;ve upped my font size on my Rstudio IDE, but hadn&amp;#8217;t yet implemented this across other IDEs I tend to use my mouse cursor to draw attention to things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An R data.table cookbook</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/an-r-data.table-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 11:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/an-r-data.table-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>For my precon on R at the end of the month I&amp;#8217;m working on the takeaway &amp;#8212; the handout. This&amp;#8217;ll be thing that makes the training day able to be put into practice immediately, and refills all those drink and sleep depleted neurons back up with R knowledge.
One of the things is a simple data.table cookbook. If you&amp;#8217;re a data.table user, what other tasks do you think should be on there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A busy month or so</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/a-busy-month-or-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/a-busy-month-or-so/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m really looking forward to a few months of user group and conference awesomeness:
 Feb 24: CaRdiff presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Feb 26: Oxford UG presenting Learning the ropes via the community Mar 4-6: Helping out at SQLBits Mar 7: SQLBits presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Mar 9: SQL Cardiff with Jen &amp;amp; Sean McCown presenting Mar 17: Diff.Net with Scott Hanselman presenting Mar 31: SQL Cardiff with the Battle of the Beards  Then even more fun kicks in with a SQLSaturday Exeter precon, a visit to unified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My R Pre-Con: SQLSat Exeter</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/my-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 10:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/my-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I covered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my post on SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m going to be doing a full day of R training on &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;April 24th&lt;/a&gt; that takes you from cabin boy to first mate in a day. You can&amp;#8217;t be captain because I&amp;#8217;m Captain&amp;#8230; until you go back to your own ship&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; you can be captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attend my day of training about R if you&amp;#8217;d like to learn R, best practices, and how to manage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s £150 (early bird) and can be booked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&amp;#8217;s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Intro to R case study</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--intro-to-r-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 09:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--intro-to-r-case-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/organised-speaking-iterative-development/&#34; title=&#34;Organised speaking – presentation design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iterative presentation design post&lt;/a&gt; I promised a case study. I thought I&amp;#8217;d cover my most presented session &lt;em&gt;Intro to R&lt;/em&gt;, in future called &lt;em&gt;Knowing your Rs from your elbow&lt;/em&gt; courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/fatherjack&#34; title=&#34;Father Jack&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@FatherJack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history&#34;&gt;A brief history&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I&amp;#8217;ve been using R for the past couple of years and spent the first months struggling with it, I wanted to give a presentation that I would have wanted to see at the beginning. Not one about random bagging and a bunch of other stats but what are the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; ways to do the fundamentals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting to my database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;performing data manipulations, summaries and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;charting my data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;producing reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few packages cover these awesomely and are much better than base R so whilst I was tackling a massive stats project, the things which took the time and stress were things I could have avoided with ease!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my intro to R, takes people through the things I wish I&amp;#8217;d been taken through thus making those first few months of R pleasant, happy times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Exeter 2015</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! The kind and crazy folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/372/eventhome.aspx&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015 homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt; accepted my submitted training day for their roster. Before I wax lyrical on the virtues of being locked in a room with me all day, I thought I&amp;#8217;d better cover the fundamentals of the event itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the awesome video&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – presentation design</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--presentation-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--presentation-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to outline my approach to presentation design, or development as I prefer to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I consider it development? Well, it&amp;#8217;s a product that can be manually done &amp;amp; delivered but with the potential to scale to thousands of users, I&amp;#8217;d rather the product be easy to maintain &amp;amp; deploy, deliver real value to the users, and keep up with cutting edge developments in the subject. Also, I call it development because now with the use of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34; title=&#34;Rmarkdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt;, I do actually code my presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-presentation-design&#34;&gt;General presentation design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read and studied a lot about presentations, some of the biggest influences being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Dr. Andrew Abela and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremepresentation.com/&#34; title=&#34;Extreme Presentation Method&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Extreme Presentation Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/buckwoody/&#34; title=&#34;Buck&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buck Woody&lt;/a&gt; and his fantastic presentation style&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2012/04/writing-better-conference-abstracts-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Brent&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brent Ozar&lt;/a&gt; and his excellent materials for presentations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Solid fundamentals in presentation training courses (things like INTRO: Intro, Need, Title, Range, Objective)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first come up with the idea for a presentation, I write the abstract for it. In the abstract I set out the tone, material covered, and outline who should attend. This abstract is my requirements doc for later me &amp;#8211; it tells me whether I&amp;#8217;m selling, educating, or entertaining and what I&amp;#8217;m doing it about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, you should always write the abstract first as not only can you write more abstracts than you can presentations but it distills the idea down and helps you think of your audience first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – prioritising events to speak at</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/organised-speaking--prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my ongoing series about presenting at community events and conferences, I wanted to cover the my personal thought process when it comes to prioritising what events I&amp;#8217;d like to speak at for my goal &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/throw-1-speak-1/&#34; title=&#34;Throw 1, Speak 1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a massive amount of awesome SQL Server and other technology events happening out there. I even throw a SQL Server lunchtime session once a week for the user group! Then of course there&amp;#8217;s all those conferences in the UK and abroad that are worth attending. So how do I event start picking out where I&amp;#8217;d like to talk, and how do I go about getting selected for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>