<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itsalocke.com/blog/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown with an existing Hugo site</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/using-blogdown-with-an-existing-hugo-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/using-blogdown-with-an-existing-hugo-site/</guid>
      <description>If you decide you want to use R in your existing Hugo blog, it’s really easy to convert over. There’s a single command you need to know from blogdown and the rest is working out your deployment process.
To create content, use the blogdown Rstudio add-in to quickly get started. This niftily reads all tags and categories from past posts to help you get going.
You can then write Rmarkdown as usual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An experiment in self-promotion – Revive Old Posts</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/an-experiment-in-self-promotion--revive-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 10:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/an-experiment-in-self-promotion--revive-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been writing (not enough) blog posts for a while now and have built up some neat stuff in the backlog if I may so myself. Alas, a lot of this doesn&amp;#8217;t get seen because it&amp;#8217;s not on the front page or in the top 5 blog posts. Sad that posts like my one on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/anchor-modelling-sixth-normal-form-databases/&#34;&gt;sixth normal form databases&lt;/a&gt; don&amp;#8217;t get enough love, I&amp;#8217;ve installed the WordPress plugin &lt;a href=&#34;https://en-gb.wordpress.org/plugins/tweet-old-post/&#34;&gt;Revive Old Posts&lt;/a&gt; (ROP) to try countering this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ItsALocke.com now with added locks</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/itsalocke.com-now-with-added-locks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 08:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/itsalocke.com-now-with-added-locks/</guid>
      <description>This blog now has some extra locks, these are in the URL bar!
It took my fantastic hosters WPEngine a little longer than I would have preferred to get a modern SSL policy. Now that they have, they did it in their typically awesome fashion. You can request a free Let&amp;#8217;s Encrypt SSL certificate from the admin dashboard, and configure how http etc should work in less than 15 minutes, and you don&amp;#8217;t have be a web wizard to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My life, my universe, my everything</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/my-life-my-universe-my-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 20:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/my-life-my-universe-my-everything/</guid>
      <description>Last year involved moving jobs to Mango as Principal Consultant, moving home, getting a dog, and Oz becoming the Purple Tadpole. That was on top of SQL Relay, copious presentations, and much travelling. By the end of the year I was pretty ill and exceedingly grumpy. Oz wasn&amp;#8217;t having a huge amount of fun either between me never being home and him having to hold the fort in a massive way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some recent posts over on the Mango blog</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/some-recent-posts-over-on-the-mango-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 17:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/some-recent-posts-over-on-the-mango-blog/</guid>
      <description>Since August, I&amp;#8217;ve had the pleasure to work at Mango Solutions, a data science consultancy, as a Principal Consultant.
In that time, I&amp;#8217;ve been to EARL London, SQL Relay, and SQL in the City, so conference season has been in full swing with more to come in the form EARL Boston next week. Surprisingly, I&amp;#8217;ve also found some time to help some customers out and write some blog posts over on the Mango site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this (bit more than a) week</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/stuff-i-read-this-bit-more-than-a-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 08:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/stuff-i-read-this-bit-more-than-a-week/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a wee while due to SQLBits disruptions and a crazy work schedule but here&amp;#8217;s some of what I&amp;#8217;ve been reading recently:
 Introverts, Extroverts, and the Complexities of Team Dynamics Azure Blob Storage introduction Kevin Kline: Advice to new bloggers Editing for people who love to write too much ProBlogger generally after KK&amp;#8217;s recommendation Why oil prices came down. and won&amp;#8217;t any more Test Driven Analysis Standardising function names in R Microservices at Netflix Microsoft closes acquisition of Revolution Analytics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/stuff-i-read-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 12:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/stuff-i-read-this-week/</guid>
      <description> ONS Style guide for writing about statistics  Your coding style can give you away Automated Tinder and the Eigenface R-help mailing list to use cage-fighting to resolve conflicts Application Containers For Cloud Computing Managing Test Data as a Database CI Component &amp;#8211; Part 1 Let the Hackers In: Experts Say Traps Better than Walls How to Write a Blog Post   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference sessions – basic web scraping in R</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/conference-sessions--basic-web-scraping-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 16:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/conference-sessions--basic-web-scraping-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a bit sad but I enjoy dissecting what sessions are submitted to conferences I&amp;#8217;m involved in or speak at. Instead of doing it primarily by eye, I&amp;#8217;ve started dabbling in web scraping in R to do it. Initially, I used RCurl and my latest snippet uses rvest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first snippet for &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlbits.com&#34; title=&#34;SQLBits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; bit of R code uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RCurl/&#34; title=&#34;RCurl on CRAN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RCurl&lt;/a&gt; but it&amp;#8217;s cumbersome, plus for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/372/schedule.aspx&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt; there is SSL to contend with. Using &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/rvest/&#34; title=&#34;rvest on CRAN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rvest&lt;/a&gt; makes it really easy and it was an excellent excuse to get around to using &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/magrittr/&#34; title=&#34;magrittr on CRAN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;magrittr&lt;/a&gt;, Hadley Wickham&amp;#8217;s pipe code paradigm for R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogger tip: I also wanted the opportunity to see how Gists imported into WordPress &amp;#8211; you just c&amp;amp;p the url in (into the code, no URL markup) and WordPress automatically pulls in the Gist. For more info on this see &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.support.wordpress.com/gist/&#34; title=&#34;Wordpress support - Gist&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WordPress&amp;#8217; article on Gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WordPress on Azure</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/setting-up-wordpress-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 22:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/setting-up-wordpress-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog was configured super rapidly with goDaddy and Azure, instead of my previous implementation on EC2.  I&amp;#8217;ve forgone the multi-site installation, with attendant subdomains, and gone for a straight wordpress Website (one of the Azure features).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had an Azure account I&amp;#8217;d gone through the billing setup for &amp;#8211; but that was really simple anyway, so getting the blog up and running consisted of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>