<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentation on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentation on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:27:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for (lightning) talks</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-07-12-ideas-lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-07-12-ideas-lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m trying to encourage more lightning talks at my user groups, and I started by writing a plea to folks at my local R user group, caRdiff. In it I included some ideas for lightning talks, and of course, these can be used as the basis for long talks too. We had some fun batting this list around and expanding it in the Cardiff dev group. I thought it was worth sharing, and getting some more ideas from you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PASS #Summit2016 submissions feedback</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-06-23-pass-summit-2016-submissions-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 11:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-06-23-pass-summit-2016-submissions-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really liked the way Brent showed us &lt;a href=&#34;https://ozar.me/2016/06/feedback-on-my-sqlpass-summit16-abstract-submissions/&#34;&gt;his feedback received&lt;/a&gt; and since mimicry is the best form of flattery, I thought I&amp;#8217;d go ahead and do it too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t get any accepted abstracts, and I&amp;#8217;m actually grateful. The recent stresses to do with the PASS dramas aside, I would have had to use 5 days holiday time, pay for flights and hotel, and then flown out a week later for MVP Summit. Now I can attend some other conferences and/or have a Christmas break! Woo hoo 😀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent presentations</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-06-01-recent-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-06-01-recent-presentations/</guid>
      <description>The last month or so has been a whirlwind of awesomeness with a veritable bevvy of user group and conference talks on my part! I thought I would share the materials with you and provide some brief thoughts on how each presentation went.
Sessions  SQL Saturday Exeter : Stats 101 London Business Analytics (LBAG) : Skilling up to code with data SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : Cut the R Learning Curve SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : R in the Microsoft Data Platform (full day of training) IT Pro Portugal : Being lazy with infrastructure  SQL Saturday Exeter My presentation, in my opinion, was exceedingly brave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-deploying documentation: Rtraining</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-12-23-auto-deploying-documentation-rtraining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 10:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-12-23-auto-deploying-documentation-rtraining/</guid>
      <description>In my last post on using GitHub, Travis-CI, and rmarkdown/knitr for automatically building and deploying documentation, I covered how I was able to do it with a containerised approach so things were faster. I also said my Rtraining repository was still too brittle to blog about. This has changed &amp;#8211; WOO HOO!
The main thanks for that goes out to the new package ezknitr from Dean Attali. ezknitr takes the pain out of working directories, making my hierarchies much more resilient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boris’ presentation agency – 356labs</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-11-11-boris-presentation-agency-356-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 09:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-11-11-boris-presentation-agency-356-labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://borishristov.com/&#34;&gt;Boris Hristrov&lt;/a&gt;, Data Platform MVP, design whizz, and all-round great guy, recently launched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.356labs.com/&#34;&gt;356labs&lt;/a&gt;. Boris wrote a great &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluralsight.com/courses/presentation-design-introduction&#34;&gt;Presentation Design course&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://preview.pluralsight.com/&#34;&gt;PluralSight&lt;/a&gt;, you can sign up for a trial of PluralSight and watch the course if you&amp;#8217;d like to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an avid reader of design stuff I did find I knew some of the things on the course, but the context and application were very helpful. Off the back of his course, I went on to produce my most visually impressive presentation slide deck to date &amp;#8211; Agile BI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look over his site and asked a few questions since I was really curious. Here are the responses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps – it’s a thing (honest)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-10-16-dataops-its-a-thing-honest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 20:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-10-16-dataops-its-a-thing-honest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I presented a &lt;a href=&#34;https://1drv.ms/p/s!AiZm2P6YHtSfjye0xDn_fuL80eSp&#34;&gt;lightning talk on DataOps&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlinthecity.red-gate.com/london-2015/&#34;&gt;SQL in the City&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic day and a great opportunity to catch up with how the database side of things is evolving to embrace &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DevOps&#34;&gt;DevOps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lightning talk was titled &lt;em&gt;DataOps &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s a thing (honest)&lt;/em&gt; and focused on what is essentially DevOps ported out of the developer sphere and into the data professional sphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Relay is here!</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-07-16-sql-relay-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 09:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-07-16-sql-relay-is-here/</guid>
      <description>SQL Relay is back on tour! Our 6th event sees us yet again touring the country bringing awesome speakers to eight cities over 2 weeks.
As usual we&amp;#8217;re improving things:
 A new platform called Attendee.Events which allows easier registration &amp;amp; speaker submission A whole bunch of webinars planned to get in the swing of things More breadth &amp;#8211; this year each event includes a dedicated track to R, machine learning etc, on top of SQL Server and business intelligence More content &amp;#8211; instead of swapping out existing slots for breadth, we added more tracks A green initiative &amp;#8230; see it on the day Improved speaker experience &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;re building on last year&amp;#8217;s fun bus with the help of SQL Sentry to make it easier and more fun for speakers to do multiple events, as well as offering first timers some mentoring as most of the organisers are also speakers  You&amp;#8217;ll see a lot of announcements about Relay over the next few months, but I hope this little post inspires you to check out our events 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom LaTeX Beamer style templates for rmarkdown</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-06-17-custom-latex-beamer-style-templates-for-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-06-17-custom-latex-beamer-style-templates-for-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been producing presentations via R using &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and outputting to either ioslides or slidify. That was excellent, because I could provide a CSS that customised the look and feel (relatively) easily*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I wanted to produce a PDF version, I couldn&amp;#8217;t make ones that look as good as the pure LaTeX versions I could make on &lt;a href=&#34;http://overleaf.com&#34;&gt;overleaf.com&lt;/a&gt;. So I started RTFMing when I wanted to replicate the look and feel from my presentation, The LaTeX Show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t want to spend a huge amount of time on it, so this little story of hack and slash may feel a bit dirty to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Portugal</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-05-18-sqlsaturday-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 09:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-05-18-sqlsaturday-portugal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlsaturday.com/369/EventHome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Portugal 2015&lt;/a&gt; has been a huge amount of fun but I&amp;#8217;ve also learnt a lot. A big thank you to the organisers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are my slides and notes from sessions I attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-bi&#34;&gt;Agile BI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My session slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Saturday Exeter: Steph &amp; Oz’s slides</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-04-26-sql-saturday-exeter-steph-ozs-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 16:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-04-26-sql-saturday-exeter-steph-ozs-slides/</guid>
      <description>Well SQL Saturday Exeter flew by. T&amp;#8217;was great catching up with people, seeing folks learn how to use (old &amp;amp; new) tools better, and just generally watching everyone having a great time at one of the best organised conferences I have the pleasure of going to.
Here are links to all the slide decks etc that we presented this weekend:
 My R: analysis to integration training day notes &amp;amp; source code My agile BI slide deck My Shiny: dashboards in R slide deck &amp;amp; source code Oz&amp;#8217;s SSRS: Beyond the basics slide deck &amp;amp; source code  If you attended any of our sessions, give us some constructive criticism!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unified.Diff: source control smells &amp; LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-04-17-unified-diff-source-control-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-04-17-unified-diff-source-control-latex/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of presenting at unified.diff, a general programming user group in Cardiff, last night and was able to debut my LaTeX show!
If you&amp;#8217;d like to talk at the group about anything tech related tweet them on @unifiedDiff. They&amp;#8217;re very flexible on time and topic so if you&amp;#8217;re based in Cardiff or are coming down to see a client, it&amp;#8217;s an easy way of delivering a talk and meeting some nice people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – improving font sizes</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-04-13-organised-speaking-improving-font-sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 12:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-04-13-organised-speaking-improving-font-sizes/</guid>
      <description>A recurring problem with my presentations is font size.
 The inclusion of code in my Rmarkdown slides was by default too small. Upping the fontsize via CSS worked ok, but when I switched to a shiny app version for my intro to shiny, it reverted and I&amp;#8217;m afraid to say I didn&amp;#8217;t notice beforehand. I use PuTTY for showing how to do some stuff in the linux command line but the font&amp;#8217;s quite small by default and Gail Shaw&amp;#8217;s tip of Magnifier in my session was tough to use I&amp;#8217;ve upped my font size on my Rstudio IDE, but hadn&amp;#8217;t yet implemented this across other IDEs I tend to use my mouse cursor to draw attention to things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My R Pre-Con: SQLSat Exeter</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-24-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 10:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-24-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I covered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my post on SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m going to be doing a full day of R training on &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;April 24th&lt;/a&gt; that takes you from cabin boy to first mate in a day. You can&amp;#8217;t be captain because I&amp;#8217;m Captain&amp;#8230; until you go back to your own ship&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; you can be captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attend my day of training about R if you&amp;#8217;d like to learn R, best practices, and how to manage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s £150 (early bird) and can be booked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&amp;#8217;s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Intro to R case study</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-21-organised-speaking-intro-r-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 09:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-21-organised-speaking-intro-r-case-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/organised-speaking-iterative-development/&#34; title=&#34;Organised speaking – presentation design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iterative presentation design post&lt;/a&gt; I promised a case study. I thought I&amp;#8217;d cover my most presented session &lt;em&gt;Intro to R&lt;/em&gt;, in future called &lt;em&gt;Knowing your Rs from your elbow&lt;/em&gt; courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/fatherjack&#34; title=&#34;Father Jack&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@FatherJack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history&#34;&gt;A brief history&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I&amp;#8217;ve been using R for the past couple of years and spent the first months struggling with it, I wanted to give a presentation that I would have wanted to see at the beginning. Not one about random bagging and a bunch of other stats but what are the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; ways to do the fundamentals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting to my database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;performing data manipulations, summaries and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;charting my data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;producing reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few packages cover these awesomely and are much better than base R so whilst I was tackling a massive stats project, the things which took the time and stress were things I could have avoided with ease!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my intro to R, takes people through the things I wish I&amp;#8217;d been taken through thus making those first few months of R pleasant, happy times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Exeter 2015</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-19-sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-19-sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! The kind and crazy folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/372/eventhome.aspx&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015 homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt; accepted my submitted training day for their roster. Before I wax lyrical on the virtues of being locked in a room with me all day, I thought I&amp;#8217;d better cover the fundamentals of the event itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the awesome video&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – presentation design</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-18-organised-speaking-iterative-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-18-organised-speaking-iterative-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to outline my approach to presentation design, or development as I prefer to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I consider it development? Well, it&amp;#8217;s a product that can be manually done &amp;amp; delivered but with the potential to scale to thousands of users, I&amp;#8217;d rather the product be easy to maintain &amp;amp; deploy, deliver real value to the users, and keep up with cutting edge developments in the subject. Also, I call it development because now with the use of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34; title=&#34;Rmarkdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt;, I do actually code my presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-presentation-design&#34;&gt;General presentation design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read and studied a lot about presentations, some of the biggest influences being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Dr. Andrew Abela and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremepresentation.com/&#34; title=&#34;Extreme Presentation Method&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Extreme Presentation Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/buckwoody/&#34; title=&#34;Buck&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buck Woody&lt;/a&gt; and his fantastic presentation style&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2012/04/writing-better-conference-abstracts-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Brent&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brent Ozar&lt;/a&gt; and his excellent materials for presentations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Solid fundamentals in presentation training courses (things like INTRO: Intro, Need, Title, Range, Objective)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first come up with the idea for a presentation, I write the abstract for it. In the abstract I set out the tone, material covered, and outline who should attend. This abstract is my requirements doc for later me &amp;#8211; it tells me whether I&amp;#8217;m selling, educating, or entertaining and what I&amp;#8217;m doing it about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, you should always write the abstract first as not only can you write more abstracts than you can presentations but it distills the idea down and helps you think of your audience first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – prioritising events to speak at</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-12-organised-speaking-prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-12-organised-speaking-prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my ongoing series about presenting at community events and conferences, I wanted to cover the my personal thought process when it comes to prioritising what events I&amp;#8217;d like to speak at for my goal &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/throw-1-speak-1/&#34; title=&#34;Throw 1, Speak 1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a massive amount of awesome SQL Server and other technology events happening out there. I even throw a SQL Server lunchtime session once a week for the user group! Then of course there&amp;#8217;s all those conferences in the UK and abroad that are worth attending. So how do I event start picking out where I&amp;#8217;d like to talk, and how do I go about getting selected for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Throw 1</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-10-organised-speaking-throw-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 09:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-10-organised-speaking-throw-1/</guid>
      <description>Not quite part of being organised at speaking, but bundled up in part of my scheduling constraints for speaking is when I&amp;#8217;m throwing user group events. Here&amp;#8217;s the details of the user groups I&amp;#8217;m planning on throwing to meet my goal of 1 user group event a month (not including lunch time sessions!)
SQL Server I run the SQL Server user group in Cardiff and have done a few years &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;m not giving it up any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Throw 1, Speak 1</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-08-throw-1-speak-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 10:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-08-throw-1-speak-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following up from my last post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/organised-speaking-session-abstracts/&#34; title=&#34;Organised speaking – session abstracts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;maintaining my session abstracts&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to cover how I&amp;#8217;m doing my scheduling this year for speaking at events. Perhaps more importantly than tech, is the intention and the planning process so I&amp;#8217;ll be covering these factors in more detail than the tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make use of Google services quite a bit, and their &lt;a href=&#34;http://calendar.google.com&#34; title=&#34;Google calendar&#34;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt; system is a great help. So this year I&amp;#8217;ve added a calendar that has all mine (and hopefully Oz&amp;#8217;s) speaking engagements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m then utilising a WordPress plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/gcal-events-list/&#34; title=&#34;Gcal events&#34;&gt;GCal events&lt;/a&gt; to connect to the calendar and pull the info into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/wheres-steff-oz/&#34; title=&#34;Where’s Steff &amp;amp; Oz?&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;throw-1-speak-1&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal this year is to throw one user group event and speak at one event each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – session abstracts</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-02-organised-speaking-session-abstracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 09:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-02-organised-speaking-session-abstracts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I spoke at 10&amp;nbsp;different events (I think) and was very lucky to be nominated in the Tribal Awards for my Intro to R session. I did just a couple of different session titles and I don&amp;#8217;t think I managed the whole process very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be an easier speaker to deal with, I&amp;#8217;m trying to be more organised so that the selection process of myself &amp;amp; topics is easier whilst also ensuring I don&amp;#8217;t develop too many presentations at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having dealt with awesome serial speakers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://koprowskit.eu/geek/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tobiasz Koprowski&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dcac.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Denny Cherry&lt;/a&gt;, from the organiser end they did a few things which made it much easier to deal with them, particularly given the breadth of topics they can cover!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Cardiff dates announced</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2014-12-29-sql-cardiff-dates-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2014-12-29-sql-cardiff-dates-announced/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year we&amp;#8217;ll be continuing to maintain evening events on Tuesday nights and lunch time events on Thursdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evening-events&#34;&gt;Evening events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we have the following events and speakers scheduled for the evening events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/218732881/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jan 27th&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; 2 hour intro to replication by David Williams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytfbpc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mar 31st&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Battle of the Beards! Tobiasz&amp;nbsp;Koprowski vs Terry McCann vs Rob Sewell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/219148389/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;May 26th&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Index Fragmentation: Internals, Analysis, and Solutions&amp;nbsp;by Paul Randal, and Steve Powell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytkblc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jul 28th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex Whittles on winning Fantasy F1 using PowerPivot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytmbmc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sep 29th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytpbgc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nov 24th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got slots in there for full hour sessions as well as lightning talks for up to half an hour long so whether you&amp;#8217;re an existing&amp;nbsp;speaker or&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.purplefrogsystems.com/blog/2014/08/why-you-should-start-presenting-at-conferences/&#34;&gt;want to improve your knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, please &lt;a href=&#34;#ContactMe&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; and book yourself in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSIS basics and gotchas – presentation and resources</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-08-16-ssis-basics-and-gotchas-presentation-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-08-16-ssis-basics-and-gotchas-presentation-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>Follow up resources / places to go for way more detail:
Stairway to SSIS
MSFT SSIS tutorial package 1
MSFT SSIS tutorial package 2
MSFT SSIS tutorial package 3
SQLCat SSIS best practices
Bob Duffy SSIS best practices
Connection Strings
The BOL for SSIS 
Design Patterns book
Design patterns 24HOP vid</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Group presentation</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-31-user-group-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 20:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-31-user-group-presentation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>