<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Group on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/user-group/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User Group on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:27:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/user-group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Data Science activities in London, June 27th – 29th</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/r-and-data-science-activities-in-london-june-27th--29th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/r-and-data-science-activities-in-london-june-27th--29th/</guid>
      <description>Locke Data will be up to some shenanigans of various stripes in the big smoke. We hope to see you at some of them!
June 26th &amp;#8212; Monday Introduction to R (Newcastle) I won&amp;#8217;t be in London for this but I&amp;#8217;ll be doing a day of Introduction to R in Newcastle. This is supporting the local user groups and costs up to £90 for the whole day.Intro to R in Newcastle, June 26th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic regressions (in R)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/logistic-regressions-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 09:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/logistic-regressions-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Logistic regressions are a great tool for predicting outcomes that are categorical. They use a transformation function based on probability to perform a linear regression. This makes them easy to interpret and implement in other systems.
Logistic regressions can be used to perform a classification for things like determining whether someone needs to go for a biopsy. They can also be used for a more nuanced view by using the probabilities of an outcome for thinks like prioritising interventions based on likelihood to default on a loan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community workshops</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/community-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/community-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Following on from when we announced the availability of our community workshops, we&amp;#8217;ve got three in the next three months that folks can attend.
May 19th &amp;#8211; Data science project in a day We&amp;#8217;ll be in Kiev, Ukraine, doing a whole data science project in a day. This is intended to give people a little bit of code, process, and critical thinking along the whole data science workflow. This will enable folks to see how it hangs together and decide where and how much they want to invest their learning in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear South Wales &amp; Bristol readers: I need your help</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/dear-south-wales--bristol-readers-i-need-your-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 12:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/dear-south-wales--bristol-readers-i-need-your-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battle of the Beards is an annual tech event in Cardiff that&amp;#8217;s previously been an evening affair but is now a day-long conference. We&amp;#8217;re hosting half-hour talks on security, infrastructure, software craftmanship, front-end development, and data visualisation. We&amp;#8217;re starting out the day with bacon baps and it just gets better from there. Tickets cost £15 and there&amp;#8217;s the option to add a donation to the charity we&amp;#8217;re supporting with the event, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecalmzone.net/&#34;&gt;Campaign Against Living Miserably&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now ticket sales are really low and without your help, we&amp;#8217;ll have to cancel the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m hoping you can help make this event succeed by doing one or both of two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://battleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&#34;&gt;register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; if it&amp;#8217;s of interest to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recommend it to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[button text=&amp;#8221;REGISTER&amp;#8221; color=&amp;#8221;orange&amp;#8221; link=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://battleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&#34;&gt;https://battleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;] [button text=&amp;#8221;TWEET&amp;#8221; color=&amp;#8221;blue&amp;#8221; link=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Hey%20%23tweeps%20-%20%23battleofthebeards%20is%20on%20March%2029th%20in%20Cardiff.%20You%20should%20check%20it%20out!%0Abattleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/home?status=Hey%20%23tweeps%20-%20%23battleofthebeards%20is%20on%20March%2029th%20in%20Cardiff.%20You%20should%20check%20it%20out!%0Abattleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing community R workshops</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/announcing-community-r-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/announcing-community-r-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of why I&amp;#8217;ve launched Locke Data is so that I can give back more to my communities. I want to give more time and more support to others. One of the first steps is doing some activities that give financial support to community groups without damaging my startup cashflow! Community R workshops that fund local user groups is the first activity I&amp;#8217;ll be trialling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s involved, and what you might want to consider if you&amp;#8217;d like to be a part of this endeavour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note to (potential) new speakers: It’s ok not to be perfect!</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/a-note-to-potential-new-speakers-its-ok-not-to-be-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 10:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/a-note-to-potential-new-speakers-its-ok-not-to-be-perfect/</guid>
      <description>This is a T-SQL Tuesday Post in response to Andy Bek&amp;#8217;s kick off about growing new speakers. You can write your own advice for new speakers, or blog your journey to speaking.
 I&amp;#8217;m always trying to encourage new speakers and the biggest fear I hear is &amp;#8220;I won&amp;#8217;t be any good at it&amp;#8221;. Well, you won&amp;#8217;t be perfect at it, that&amp;#8217;s for sure. You may start off really bad at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections: SQL Relay is coming</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/reflections-sql-relay-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 08:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/reflections-sql-relay-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty quiet recently, I haven&amp;#8217;t presented much, I haven&amp;#8217;t blogged much, I haven&amp;#8217;t worked on my open source projects much. All my energy left over from my major work project has been going into SQL Relay. SQL Relay is an ambitious project every year. We organise a conference that goes on tour. In previous years, I&amp;#8217;ve gone to 8 cities over two weeks. Over the past 4 years, I&amp;#8217;ve been part of organising 30 conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsoring community events (SCE)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sponsoring-community-events-sce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sponsoring-community-events-sce/</guid>
      <description>Sponsoring community events &amp;#8211; is it right for you? This series of posts will take you through the things you need to know to help you decide.
Over the coming weeks, this new series will go through the in&amp;#8217;s and out&amp;#8217;s of sponsoring community events. Community events are fantastic from an attendee perspective, but when you&amp;#8217;re handing over cash you need to know what you&amp;#8217;re letting yourself in for and how you get return on investment (ROI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving back with code</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/giving-back-with-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/giving-back-with-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From code in answers on Stack Overflow to R packages or full programs, there&amp;#8217;s a lot of code being written and given away. This post examines some of the reasons why the people writing all that code do it, why you should consider giving back with code, and how you can get started. Finally, I cap it all off with perspectives from some of my favourite coders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#reasons&#34;&gt;Because reasons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getstarted&#34;&gt;Get started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#perspectives&#34;&gt;Perspectives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasons&#34;&gt;Because reasons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why you should consider writing code and making it available for public consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;altruistic&#34;&gt;Altruistic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re writing something to achieve a task, odds are someone else would have to write the same code &amp;#8211; why not help them out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#8217;re using a lot of open source software, whether you realise it or not. By open sourcing your code, you get to pay it forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To give others something to contribute to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unknown quantities are risky hires, put your code out there for the world to see and employers get to see what you can do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop your skills for the next job, the one that requires you to be more skilled in something than you are now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get to interact with a lot of different people who you build credibility with, and hopefully friendships!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-oneself&#34;&gt;For oneself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generally speaking, the more code you write, the better your coding skills so if you want to improve your skills this is an ideal way to do it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the sheer fun of doing cool stuff, especially if you don&amp;#8217;t get to do cool stuff in the day job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To do it &amp;#8220;the way it should be done&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for (lightning) talks</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/ideas-for-lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/ideas-for-lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m trying to encourage more lightning talks at my user groups, and I started by writing a plea to folks at my local R user group, caRdiff. In it I included some ideas for lightning talks, and of course, these can be used as the basis for long talks too. We had some fun batting this list around and expanding it in the Cardiff dev group. I thought it was worth sharing, and getting some more ideas from you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad ways to run a user group</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/bad-ways-to-run-a-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 12:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/bad-ways-to-run-a-user-group/</guid>
      <description>I love user groups and I always want there to be more. I&amp;#8217;m not a perfect organiser but I run reasonable groups. When I see organisers doing it badly, it makes me sad. There&amp;#8217;s lots of great ways to run a user group, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d cover some of the bad ways to run a user group. The anti-patterns if you will 😀
Don&amp;#8217;t advertise Your group isn&amp;#8217;t on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent presentations</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/recent-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/recent-presentations/</guid>
      <description>The last month or so has been a whirlwind of awesomeness with a veritable bevvy of user group and conference talks on my part! I thought I would share the materials with you and provide some brief thoughts on how each presentation went.
Sessions  SQL Saturday Exeter : Stats 101 London Business Analytics (LBAG) : Skilling up to code with data SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : Cut the R Learning Curve SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : R in the Microsoft Data Platform (full day of training) IT Pro Portugal : Being lazy with infrastructure  SQL Saturday Exeter My presentation, in my opinion, was exceedingly brave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRday location voting now open</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/satrday-location-voting-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 15:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/satrday-location-voting-now-open/</guid>
      <description>satRdays, free R conferences, are a project being supported by the R Consortium. When Gergely and I submitted our proposal, we said we&amp;#8217;d be supporting three conferences:
 Budapest, Hungary (Gergely&amp;#8217;s home turf) Somewhere in the US Somewhere else in the world  We&amp;#8217;ve had an overwhelming response with 40 submitted conferences but for the fully-funded ones, there can only be three. We are looking at how the runners up can do the next wave of events but we want to get the ball rolling on the first three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRdays are go!</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/satrdays-are-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 13:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/satrdays-are-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m very pleased to say that the R Consortium agreed to the support the satRday project!
The idea kicked off in November and I was over the moon with the response from the community, then we garnered support before submitting to the Consortium and I must have looped the moon a few times as we had more than 500 responses. Now the R Consortium are supporting us and we can turn all that enthusiasm into action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@SQLCardiff: Return of the Beard (2016-03-30)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlcardiff-return-of-the-beard-2016-03-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlcardiff-return-of-the-beard-2016-03-30/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick heads up to peeps in and around Cardiff, Wales. Later this month we&amp;#8217;re holding Battle of the Beards: Return of the Beard. Fantastic speakers with resplendent beards are joining us for our 6 sq. ft of pizza to present on advanced SQL Tricks, using PowerBI as a DBA, and stepping up to the challenge of the last minute audit.
This is a great chance to meet folks interested in the Microsoft Data Platform and learn from some incredibly knowledgable speakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRdays: final push</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/satrdays-final-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/satrdays-final-push/</guid>
      <description>I talked back in November about the idea of an RSaturday, which were free community-driven conferences on R. Since then, we created a GitHub repository and started hammering out the details for satRdays. The current proposal consists of:
 A name: satRday A proposition: Free/cheap (&amp;lt;£30) conferences organised by user groups around the world. Attendees get more access to training in R, with a much lower cost-barrier. We develop more speakers on R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturdays but for R?</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlsaturdays-but-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 19:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlsaturdays-but-for-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: Proposal now being developed after fantastic community support. Check out satRdays on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stephlocke/RSaturday-proposal&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and contribute your opinions!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a contact from a very nice chap in Dallas a month ago about whether in the R world we do anything like SQLSaturdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about the SQLSaturdays he said was not that they&amp;#8217;re free (well it helps!) but that they&amp;#8217;re on his time. Developing his skills was something he couldn&amp;#8217;t get signed off by his boss so he wanted to be able to do it by himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In answer to the question of whether there are local(ish) weekend conferences happening regularly for R, my answer was &amp;#8220;not really&amp;#8221; and it&amp;#8217;s a shame because the R community is fantastic. I started thinking about why we don&amp;#8217;t have them and what would be needed to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free / cheap regional small-medium conferences are a must for growing user knowledge and speakers in R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Relay is here!</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sql-relay-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 09:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sql-relay-is-here/</guid>
      <description>SQL Relay is back on tour! Our 6th event sees us yet again touring the country bringing awesome speakers to eight cities over 2 weeks.
As usual we&amp;#8217;re improving things:
 A new platform called Attendee.Events which allows easier registration &amp;amp; speaker submission A whole bunch of webinars planned to get in the swing of things More breadth &amp;#8211; this year each event includes a dedicated track to R, machine learning etc, on top of SQL Server and business intelligence More content &amp;#8211; instead of swapping out existing slots for breadth, we added more tracks A green initiative &amp;#8230; see it on the day Improved speaker experience &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;re building on last year&amp;#8217;s fun bus with the help of SQL Sentry to make it easier and more fun for speakers to do multiple events, as well as offering first timers some mentoring as most of the organisers are also speakers  You&amp;#8217;ll see a lot of announcements about Relay over the next few months, but I hope this little post inspires you to check out our events 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many is too many conferences?</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/how-many-is-too-many-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 17:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/how-many-is-too-many-conferences/</guid>
      <description>The SQL Server community has a lot of events. In the UK alone this year we will have/had in 2015:
 more than 75 user group meetings 5 SQL Saturdays 8 days of Relay 1 SQL in the City 3 to 5 days of SQLBits possibly a SQL Santa and probably more that I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten or not know about at the time of writing this  You could attend 2 days of conference per month (cpm from now on) on average in the UK alone, just at dedicated SQL events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unified.Diff: source control smells &amp; LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/unified.diff-source-control-smells--latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/unified.diff-source-control-smells--latex/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of presenting at unified.diff, a general programming user group in Cardiff, last night and was able to debut my LaTeX show!
If you&amp;#8217;d like to talk at the group about anything tech related tweet them on @unifiedDiff. They&amp;#8217;re very flexible on time and topic so if you&amp;#8217;re based in Cardiff or are coming down to see a client, it&amp;#8217;s an easy way of delivering a talk and meeting some nice people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming social anxiety to attend user groups</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/overcoming-social-anxiety-to-attend-user-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 14:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/overcoming-social-anxiety-to-attend-user-groups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some people it might sound silly, but a frequent reason why people don&amp;#8217;t sign up or don&amp;#8217;t make it to their local user group is to do with social anxiety. I totally understand this &amp;#8211; a room full of people you don&amp;#8217;t know can be a daunting experience. I still get nervous when attending a new user group for the first time and I run three user groups, and speak at user groups and conferences all round the country!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post takes you through the worries, and explains how I&amp;#8217;ve approached some of the issues. Hopefully, this&amp;#8217;ll help you get more people in to your local user group and learning, whether it&amp;#8217;s because you have the tools to help yourself, or understand and can help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A busy month or so</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/a-busy-month-or-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/a-busy-month-or-so/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m really looking forward to a few months of user group and conference awesomeness:
 Feb 24: CaRdiff presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Feb 26: Oxford UG presenting Learning the ropes via the community Mar 4-6: Helping out at SQLBits Mar 7: SQLBits presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Mar 9: SQL Cardiff with Jen &amp;amp; Sean McCown presenting Mar 17: Diff.Net with Scott Hanselman presenting Mar 31: SQL Cardiff with the Battle of the Beards  Then even more fun kicks in with a SQLSaturday Exeter precon, a visit to unified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Exeter 2015</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! The kind and crazy folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/372/eventhome.aspx&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015 homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt; accepted my submitted training day for their roster. Before I wax lyrical on the virtues of being locked in a room with me all day, I thought I&amp;#8217;d better cover the fundamentals of the event itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the awesome video&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – presentation design</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--presentation-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--presentation-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to outline my approach to presentation design, or development as I prefer to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I consider it development? Well, it&amp;#8217;s a product that can be manually done &amp;amp; delivered but with the potential to scale to thousands of users, I&amp;#8217;d rather the product be easy to maintain &amp;amp; deploy, deliver real value to the users, and keep up with cutting edge developments in the subject. Also, I call it development because now with the use of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34; title=&#34;Rmarkdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt;, I do actually code my presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-presentation-design&#34;&gt;General presentation design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read and studied a lot about presentations, some of the biggest influences being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Dr. Andrew Abela and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremepresentation.com/&#34; title=&#34;Extreme Presentation Method&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Extreme Presentation Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/buckwoody/&#34; title=&#34;Buck&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buck Woody&lt;/a&gt; and his fantastic presentation style&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2012/04/writing-better-conference-abstracts-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Brent&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brent Ozar&lt;/a&gt; and his excellent materials for presentations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Solid fundamentals in presentation training courses (things like INTRO: Intro, Need, Title, Range, Objective)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first come up with the idea for a presentation, I write the abstract for it. In the abstract I set out the tone, material covered, and outline who should attend. This abstract is my requirements doc for later me &amp;#8211; it tells me whether I&amp;#8217;m selling, educating, or entertaining and what I&amp;#8217;m doing it about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, you should always write the abstract first as not only can you write more abstracts than you can presentations but it distills the idea down and helps you think of your audience first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: The first CaRdiff R User Group meeting</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/review-the-first-cardiff-r-user-group-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 14:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/review-the-first-cardiff-r-user-group-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night was the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-R-User-Group/&#34; title=&#34;CaRdiff R User Group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cardiff R User Group&lt;/a&gt; event. There were 6 people registered out of 24 CaRdiffians. In the end we had 8 people show up &amp;#8211; so a whopping third of our current membership base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we sat around the booth eating chips and drinking beer, we covered our experiences learning R to date, the trials and tribulations of our jobs and why you shouldn&amp;#8217;t drop a barbell on your nose. We had great discussions and most of us came away with new R functionality to look at!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to initially go with the three session formats I&amp;#8217;d proposed and see how things go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-R-User-Group/events/219775500/&#34; title=&#34;First TalkR session&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TalkRs&lt;/a&gt;: evening events with talks and socialising&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-R-User-Group/events/219691058/&#34; title=&#34;First LearnRs session&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LearnRs&lt;/a&gt;: after work sessions focused on learning some new bit of R&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-R-User-Group/events/219476537/&#34; title=&#34;First LunchRs session&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LunchRs&lt;/a&gt;: quick lunchtime sessions to talk through a problem with someone else and hopefully solve it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – prioritising events to speak at</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my ongoing series about presenting at community events and conferences, I wanted to cover the my personal thought process when it comes to prioritising what events I&amp;#8217;d like to speak at for my goal &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/throw-1-speak-1/&#34; title=&#34;Throw 1, Speak 1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a massive amount of awesome SQL Server and other technology events happening out there. I even throw a SQL Server lunchtime session once a week for the user group! Then of course there&amp;#8217;s all those conferences in the UK and abroad that are worth attending. So how do I event start picking out where I&amp;#8217;d like to talk, and how do I go about getting selected for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Throw 1</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--throw-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 09:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--throw-1/</guid>
      <description>Not quite part of being organised at speaking, but bundled up in part of my scheduling constraints for speaking is when I&amp;#8217;m throwing user group events. Here&amp;#8217;s the details of the user groups I&amp;#8217;m planning on throwing to meet my goal of 1 user group event a month (not including lunch time sessions!)
SQL Server I run the SQL Server user group in Cardiff and have done a few years &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;m not giving it up any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Cardiff R User Group</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/starting-the-cardiff-r-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 15:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/starting-the-cardiff-r-user-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days any hobby of mine ends up with a user group if there isn&amp;#8217;t one already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of value I derive from being able to hear experts in their fields talk about whether they&amp;#8217;re on stage or in the audience is phenomenal. Also, it&amp;#8217;s really great way to meet like-minded people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with the benefits in mind, 2 years of R under my belt, and a new starter in work, the time seemed ripe for an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-R-User-Group/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;  title=&#34;Cardiff R&#34;&gt;R user group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Throw 1, Speak 1</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--throw-1-speak-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 10:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--throw-1-speak-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following up from my last post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/organised-speaking-session-abstracts/&#34; title=&#34;Organised speaking – session abstracts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;maintaining my session abstracts&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to cover how I&amp;#8217;m doing my scheduling this year for speaking at events. Perhaps more importantly than tech, is the intention and the planning process so I&amp;#8217;ll be covering these factors in more detail than the tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make use of Google services quite a bit, and their &lt;a href=&#34;http://calendar.google.com&#34; title=&#34;Google calendar&#34;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt; system is a great help. So this year I&amp;#8217;ve added a calendar that has all mine (and hopefully Oz&amp;#8217;s) speaking engagements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m then utilising a WordPress plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/gcal-events-list/&#34; title=&#34;Gcal events&#34;&gt;GCal events&lt;/a&gt; to connect to the calendar and pull the info into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/wheres-steff-oz/&#34; title=&#34;Where’s Steff &amp;amp; Oz?&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;throw-1-speak-1&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal this year is to throw one user group event and speak at one event each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – session abstracts</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--session-abstracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 09:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/organised-speaking--session-abstracts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I spoke at 10&amp;nbsp;different events (I think) and was very lucky to be nominated in the Tribal Awards for my Intro to R session. I did just a couple of different session titles and I don&amp;#8217;t think I managed the whole process very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be an easier speaker to deal with, I&amp;#8217;m trying to be more organised so that the selection process of myself &amp;amp; topics is easier whilst also ensuring I don&amp;#8217;t develop too many presentations at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having dealt with awesome serial speakers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://koprowskit.eu/geek/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tobiasz Koprowski&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dcac.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Denny Cherry&lt;/a&gt;, from the organiser end they did a few things which made it much easier to deal with them, particularly given the breadth of topics they can cover!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Cardiff dates announced</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sql-cardiff-dates-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sql-cardiff-dates-announced/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year we&amp;#8217;ll be continuing to maintain evening events on Tuesday nights and lunch time events on Thursdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evening-events&#34;&gt;Evening events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we have the following events and speakers scheduled for the evening events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/218732881/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jan 27th&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; 2 hour intro to replication by David Williams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytfbpc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mar 31st&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Battle of the Beards! Tobiasz&amp;nbsp;Koprowski vs Terry McCann vs Rob Sewell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/219148389/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;May 26th&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Index Fragmentation: Internals, Analysis, and Solutions&amp;nbsp;by Paul Randal, and Steve Powell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytkblc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jul 28th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex Whittles on winning Fantasy F1 using PowerPivot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytmbmc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sep 29th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Cardiff-SQL-Server-User-Group/events/gxqqclytpbgc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nov 24th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got slots in there for full hour sessions as well as lightning talks for up to half an hour long so whether you&amp;#8217;re an existing&amp;nbsp;speaker or&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.purplefrogsystems.com/blog/2014/08/why-you-should-start-presenting-at-conferences/&#34;&gt;want to improve your knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, please &lt;a href=&#34;#ContactMe&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; and book yourself in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLRelay Cardiff – Nov 13th</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlrelay-cardiff--nov-13th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 20:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sqlrelay-cardiff--nov-13th/</guid>
      <description>After dipping Cardiff&amp;#8217;s collective toes into the world of local SQL Server conferences, we&amp;#8217;re doing it again in November. We&amp;#8217;re taking registrations, and volunteers are always welcome. If an all day conference is a bit too much, why not try out a lunchtime or evening event?
There are 9 other events around the country which you can attend as well as / instead of Cardiff, including Bristol where I&amp;#8217;ve the privilege of speaking along with some excellent folk like Klaus Aschenbrenner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing for SQLRelay – two weeks in</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/marketing-for-sqlrelay--two-weeks-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 18:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/marketing-for-sqlrelay--two-weeks-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Further to &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/marketing-for-sqlrelay-in-the-beginning/&#34; title=&#34;Marketing for SQLRelay – In the beginning&#34;&gt;the last post&lt;/a&gt; introducing my trials and tribulations, and a hectic week or two we&amp;#8217;ve made excellent progress on the Relay.  I&amp;#8217;ve enlisted Mark (@tsqltidy) the chair for the Relay and others to assist with the twittering and other activities which has really held me reduce my workload substantially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All ten venues are going ahead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id=&#34;agendatable&#34; style=&#34;width: 95%;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
      Location
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
      Date
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Monday 11th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Southampton&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Tuesday 12th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cardiff&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Wednesday 13th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Birmingham&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Thursday 14th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hertfordshire &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Friday 15th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Newcastle&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Monday 25th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manchester&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Tuesday 26th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Norwich&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Wednesday 27th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bristol&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Thursday 28th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.co.uk&#34;&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Friday 29th Nov 2013
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugomore42&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-8217-s-been-done-so-far&#34;&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s been done so far?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;facebook&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have I been doing to try to make this a successful marketing channel:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing for SQLRelay – In the beginning</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/marketing-for-sqlrelay--in-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 11:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/marketing-for-sqlrelay--in-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After organising &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlrelay-stef.eventbrite.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLRelay&lt;/a&gt; for June 24th in Cardiff, as part of the national series of 8 events.  We&amp;#8217;re gearing up for November with the aim of being able to capitalise on the growing knowledge of SQL Server 2014 CTP and pushing the Relay into a less busy part of the UK community schedule.  The difficulty is that where we had more than 6 months to prep for the previous Relay, this time round we had less than 5.  What this means for me, is not only do I want to run a bigger and better Cardiff event, but I also (being a glutton for punishment) took on spearheading the marketing efforts for the whole shebang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details will be released next week on the launch, but given my lack of knowledge about anything social media this has already been a major undertaking for me, and I thought it might be of value for me, future me, and my dear readers to compile information and learnings as I go along so that it&amp;#8217;s easier to implement in future for other marketing endeavours.  It also provides an area for discussion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSIS basics and gotchas – presentation and resources</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/ssis-basics-and-gotchas--presentation-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/ssis-basics-and-gotchas--presentation-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>Follow up resources / places to go for way more detail:
Stairway to SSIS
MSFT SSIS tutorial package 1
MSFT SSIS tutorial package 2
MSFT SSIS tutorial package 3
SQLCat SSIS best practices
Bob Duffy SSIS best practices
Connection Strings
The BOL for SSIS 
Design Patterns book
Design patterns 24HOP vid</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Group presentation</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/user-group-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 20:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/user-group-presentation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>