<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 08:02:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving automatic document production with R</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/improving-automatic-document-production-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 08:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/improving-automatic-document-production-with-r/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I describe the latest iteration of my automatic document production with R. It improves upon the methods used in Rtraining, and previous work on this topic can read by going to the auto deploying R documentation tag.
I keep banging on about this area because reproducible research / analytical document pipelines is an area I&amp;#8217;ve a keen interest in. I see it as a core part of DataOps as it&amp;#8217;s vital for helping us ensure our models and analysis are correct in data science and boosting our productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISP-DM and why you should know about it</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/crisp-dm-and-why-you-should-know-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 15:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/crisp-dm-and-why-you-should-know-about-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cross Industry Standard Process for Data Mining (CRISP-DM) was a concept developed 20 years ago now. I&amp;#8217;ve read about it in various data mining and related books and it&amp;#8217;s come in very handy over the years. In this post, I&amp;#8217;ll outline what the model is and why you should know about it, even if it has that terribly out of vogue phrase data mining in it! 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-width=&#34;525&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    Data / R people. Do you know what the CRISP-DM model is?
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;mdash; Steph Locke (@SteffLocke) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SteffLocke/status/818148292060213250&#34;&gt;January 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack all the things!</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/slack-all-the-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 14:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/slack-all-the-things/</guid>
      <description>Slack all the things! OK, if you haven&amp;#8217;t heard of it before Slack is kinda like IRC, kinda like Dropbox, kinda like a lot of things &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s a neat place to bring together communications between your team or community, and the integrations allow you to pipe in external feeds like twitter activity or RSS. It&amp;#8217;s a great way of collaborating online and I&amp;#8217;ve found it especially useful not just within a company but within a global community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps – it’s a thing (honest)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/dataops--its-a-thing-honest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 20:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/dataops--its-a-thing-honest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I presented a &lt;a href=&#34;https://1drv.ms/p/s!AiZm2P6YHtSfjye0xDn_fuL80eSp&#34;&gt;lightning talk on DataOps&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlinthecity.red-gate.com/london-2015/&#34;&gt;SQL in the City&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic day and a great opportunity to catch up with how the database side of things is evolving to embrace &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DevOps&#34;&gt;DevOps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lightning talk was titled &lt;em&gt;DataOps &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s a thing (honest)&lt;/em&gt; and focused on what is essentially DevOps ported out of the developer sphere and into the data professional sphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/stuff-i-read-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 08:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/stuff-i-read-this-week/</guid>
      <description> Maker&amp;#8217;s Schedule, Manager&amp;#8217;s Schedule  Reality Check: Counseling for Developer Hero Worshippers Comments on Joining Microsoft Giving back for the future of open source SQLBits videos &amp;#8211; watched not read though What they don&amp;#8217;t tell you about public speaking Toxicity in Reddit Communities: a Journey to the Darkest Depths of the Interwebs Owner of a Credit Card Processor Is Setting a New Minimum Wage: $70,000 a Year Use Datazen for free if you have SQL Server Enterprise   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bride of Frankenstein: TFS &#43; R</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/bride-of-frankenstein-tfs---r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 10:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/bride-of-frankenstein-tfs---r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The unholy abomination of trying to use TFS as my central repository for my R code over the past year has been tough and you may or not be looking at the screen as if I&amp;#8217;m a crazy fool for even trying. Of course, now I have good news, because I&amp;#8217;ve broken the back of the main issue I had with TFS. The crucial link was being able to programatically create Git repositories within a single project for small projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the API, I&amp;#8217;ve been able to write an &lt;a title=&#34;tfsR&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/stephlocke/tfsR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt; with functions that now save me at least 15 minutes of time and effort each time I want a new project. So I can happily holler &amp;#8220;IT&amp;#8217;S ALIVE!!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spell check your spreadsheets</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/spell-check-your-spreadsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 10:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/spell-check-your-spreadsheets/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick tip for spreadsheet users about spellchecking in Excel.
Firstly, yes you can spell check a spreadsheet.
Secondly, you do it either by going to Review &amp;gt; Check Spelling, or more easily by hitting F7 on your keyboard.
Please, please spellcheck your work &amp;#8211; it makes your work much more professional and saves you having to do it manually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photoshop image macro (or something even better!)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/photoshop-image-macro-or-something-even-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 10:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/photoshop-image-macro-or-something-even-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time in Photoshop for someone in BI. Between cleaning up images, building logos for my latest project, or producing material for user groups, I probably use it at least once a week. Through it all, I usually need to produce variants, in different file formats and sizes. So it can quickly become a dozen uses of the Save As&amp;#8230; or Save for Web functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate manual work, so you can see why it was frustrating in the extreme. Then I realised how silly I was being by not having already googled for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while because my keyword searches weren&amp;#8217;t the terms Photoshop use but I found the Secret Sauce. And if you&amp;#8217;re the sort of person who&amp;#8217;d type &amp;#8220;photoshop image macro&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; here&amp;#8217;s how you do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>