<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sponsoring Community Events on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/sponsoring-community-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sponsoring Community Events on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 08:28:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/sponsoring-community-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building your booth presence (SCE p4)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/building-your-booth-presence-sce-p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 08:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/building-your-booth-presence-sce-p4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building your booth presence is the fourth instalment of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/sponsoring-community-events/&#34;&gt;Sponsoring Community Events&lt;/a&gt; series aimed at helping companies get to grips with sponsoring community events and getting the most out of them. This post covers some of the things that you should be thinking about when you are planning on having a booth at an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Sponsorship Opportunities (SCE p2)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/assessing-sponsorship-opportunities-sce-p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 10:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/assessing-sponsorship-opportunities-sce-p2/</guid>
      <description>Assessing Sponsorship Opportunities is the second instalment of the Sponsoring Community Events series aimed at helping companies get to grips with sponsoring community events and getting the most out of them. This post covers some of the things that you should be thinking about when you are considering sponsoring an event.
What&amp;#8217;s the point? Before entering into a sponsorship agreement you need to have a firm idea of what you&amp;#8217;re hoping to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsorship Basics (SCE p1)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sponsorship-basics-sce-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 09:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sponsorship-basics-sce-p1/</guid>
      <description>Sponsorship Basics is the first installment of the Sponsoring Community Events series aimed at helping companies get to grips with sponsoring community events, and getting the most out of them.
What is a community event? A community event is one organised by members of the community, as opposed to one run by one or more companies with a financial interest in the community. These events are fundamentally different because they are not being run for profit, instead, they&amp;#8217;re run to assist other members of the community to increase their skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsoring community events (SCE)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sponsoring-community-events-sce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/sponsoring-community-events-sce/</guid>
      <description>Sponsoring community events &amp;#8211; is it right for you? This series of posts will take you through the things you need to know to help you decide.
Over the coming weeks, this new series will go through the in&amp;#8217;s and out&amp;#8217;s of sponsoring community events. Community events are fantastic from an attendee perspective, but when you&amp;#8217;re handing over cash you need to know what you&amp;#8217;re letting yourself in for and how you get return on investment (ROI).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>