<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stuff I Read This Week on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/stuff-i-read-this-week/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stuff I Read This Week on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 08:20:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/stuff-i-read-this-week/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-04-15-stuff-i-read-this-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 08:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-04-15-stuff-i-read-this-week-3/</guid>
      <description> Maker&amp;#8217;s Schedule, Manager&amp;#8217;s Schedule  Reality Check: Counseling for Developer Hero Worshippers Comments on Joining Microsoft Giving back for the future of open source SQLBits videos &amp;#8211; watched not read though What they don&amp;#8217;t tell you about public speaking Toxicity in Reddit Communities: a Journey to the Darkest Depths of the Interwebs Owner of a Credit Card Processor Is Setting a New Minimum Wage: $70,000 a Year Use Datazen for free if you have SQL Server Enterprise   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this (bit more than a) week</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-04-07-stuff-i-read-this-bit-more-than-a-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 08:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-04-07-stuff-i-read-this-bit-more-than-a-week/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a wee while due to SQLBits disruptions and a crazy work schedule but here&amp;#8217;s some of what I&amp;#8217;ve been reading recently:
 Introverts, Extroverts, and the Complexities of Team Dynamics Azure Blob Storage introduction Kevin Kline: Advice to new bloggers Editing for people who love to write too much ProBlogger generally after KK&amp;#8217;s recommendation Why oil prices came down. and won&amp;#8217;t any more Test Driven Analysis Standardising function names in R Microservices at Netflix Microsoft closes acquisition of Revolution Analytics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-27-stuff-i-read-this-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 13:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-27-stuff-i-read-this-week-2/</guid>
      <description> The Unbearable Lightness of Tweeting  Hadley Wickham: Impact the world by being useful Academics should be made accountable for exaggerations in press releases about their own work Why Complex Decisions Inevitably Take Weeks Six sentence emails that get fast responses Average house prices: how expensive is your area? FCA Consumer Spotlight &amp;#8212; segmenting retail financial customers Making R Files Executable (under Windows) Shipping Culture Is Hurting Us   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-22-stuff-i-read-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 12:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-22-stuff-i-read-this-week/</guid>
      <description> ONS Style guide for writing about statistics  Your coding style can give you away Automated Tinder and the Eigenface R-help mailing list to use cage-fighting to resolve conflicts Application Containers For Cloud Computing Managing Test Data as a Database CI Component &amp;#8211; Part 1 Let the Hackers In: Experts Say Traps Better than Walls How to Write a Blog Post   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-13-stuff-read-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 15:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-13-stuff-read-week/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s a selection of articles etc. that I found really interesting this week:
 Gendered Language in Teacher Reviews Knowledge units &amp;#8211; the atoms of statistical education SQLBits in The Register Paul Randal: Want to be mentored by me? Replacing Middle Management with APIs R in Business Intelligence The RHS assignment operator in R Ooh R Can Microsoft make R easy?  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>