<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc Technology on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/categories/misc-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc Technology on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 08:24:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/categories/misc-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to change “No match found!” on your no-code Q&amp;A bot</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-05-22-change-no-match-found-no-code-qa-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 08:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-05-22-change-no-match-found-no-code-qa-bot/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I blogged about building a no-code Q&amp;amp;A bot for your website. One little niggle I had with the bot was the response when it could match a user input to a Q&amp;amp;A. I wondered how to change &amp;#8220;No match found!&amp;#8221;.
I looked around the qnamaker.ai site and couldn&amp;#8217;t find a place I could change this. I submitted some feedback and the great people at the other of the Q&amp;amp;A site responded super quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy-peasy Q&amp;A bot</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-05-15-easy-peasy-qa-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-05-15-easy-peasy-qa-bot/</guid>
      <description>Everyone seems to have a live chat option for their site but I&amp;#8217;m frequently away, so I wanted something that people could talk to interactively. This is a perfect scenario for a Q&amp;amp;A bot. Microsoft takes a ton of the pain out of Q&amp;amp;A bots, and it was much easier than I thought to get it added to my WordPress blog. Here is a how to do it for your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an R training environment</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-04-24-r-training-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 08:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-04-24-r-training-environment/</guid>
      <description>I recently delivered a day of training at SQLBits and I really upped my game in terms of infrastructure for it. The resultant solution was super smooth and mitigated all the install issues and preparation for attendees. This meant we got to spend the whole day doing R, instead of troubleshooting.
I&amp;#8217;m so happy with the solution for an online R training environment that I want to share the solution, so you can take it and use it for when you need to do training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip: knitr Python Windows setup checklist</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-02-22-quick-tip-knitr-python-windows-setup-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 16:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-02-22-quick-tip-knitr-python-windows-setup-checklist/</guid>
      <description>One of the nifty things about using R is that you can use it for many different purposes and even other languages!
If you want to use Python in your knitr docs or the newish RStudio R notebook functionality, you might encounter some fiddliness getting all the moving parts running on Windows. This is a quick knitr Python Windows setup checklist to make sure you don&amp;#8217;t miss any important steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Data and Docker</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-02-08-talking-data-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-02-08-talking-data-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>If you need to know about persisting data in the world of containers then I recently did a talk and a spot on a podcast that should help you out. My NDC London talk Data + Docker = Disconbobulating? cover the basics and architectural decisions. In my podcast spot Data and Docker on .Net Rocks we go into more depth about the architectural decisions facing you when working with data and Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISP-DM and why you should know about it</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-01-13-crisp-dm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 15:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-01-13-crisp-dm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cross Industry Standard Process for Data Mining (CRISP-DM) was a concept developed 20 years ago now. I&amp;#8217;ve read about it in various data mining and related books and it&amp;#8217;s come in very handy over the years. In this post, I&amp;#8217;ll outline what the model is and why you should know about it, even if it has that terribly out of vogue phrase data mining in it! 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-width=&#34;525&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    Data / R people. Do you know what the CRISP-DM model is?
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;mdash; Steph Locke (@SteffLocke) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SteffLocke/status/818148292060213250&#34;&gt;January 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip: Passing values to a bash script</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-30-passing-values-bash-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 14:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-30-passing-values-bash-script/</guid>
      <description>This is a very quick post on how you can make a bash script that allows you to provide it values via the command line. Passing values to a bash script uses a 1-based array convention inside the script, that are referenced by prefixing with $ inside the script.
This means that if I provide .\dummyscript.sh value1 value2, inside the dummyscript.sh I can retrieve these by referencing their positions:
echo $1 + $2  For improved clarity, you could assign them to new variables</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GirlswithDeepPockets.com</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-28-girlswithdeeppockets-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 11:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-28-girlswithdeeppockets-com/</guid>
      <description>Ok, this post is about one of my latest crazy/harebrained/whacky ideas.
I&amp;#8217;m fed up of having to carry my Galaxy Note 3 in my hand. I can&amp;#8217;t stand handbags and most women&amp;#8217;s clothing items don&amp;#8217;t have pockets or the pockets are insufficient. Given how easy it is to build a website these days, I thought I&amp;#8217;d become a sofa warrior for the campaign for pockets. I&amp;#8217;ve made a site and aim to make it an open &amp;amp; technical backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 useful CSS sites</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-27-5-useful-css-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-27-5-useful-css-sites/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a lot of web development recently, primarily via the magical Hugo platform. Between it and the great themes for it, it&amp;#8217;s making website building fairly painless. Of course, each theme often needs customising to the relevant brand a given site is for. That customising is usually just one by some fonts and by tweaking the CSS.*
I&amp;#8217;ve been relying on some old, and some very new, funky tools to help with CSS hacking and I thought I would share them, in case they should prove useful to you in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving back with code</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-07-20-giving-back-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-07-20-giving-back-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From code in answers on Stack Overflow to R packages or full programs, there&amp;#8217;s a lot of code being written and given away. This post examines some of the reasons why the people writing all that code do it, why you should consider giving back with code, and how you can get started. Finally, I cap it all off with perspectives from some of my favourite coders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#reasons&#34;&gt;Because reasons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getstarted&#34;&gt;Get started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#perspectives&#34;&gt;Perspectives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasons&#34;&gt;Because reasons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why you should consider writing code and making it available for public consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;altruistic&#34;&gt;Altruistic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re writing something to achieve a task, odds are someone else would have to write the same code &amp;#8211; why not help them out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#8217;re using a lot of open source software, whether you realise it or not. By open sourcing your code, you get to pay it forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To give others something to contribute to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;career&#34;&gt;Career&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unknown quantities are risky hires, put your code out there for the world to see and employers get to see what you can do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop your skills for the next job, the one that requires you to be more skilled in something than you are now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get to interact with a lot of different people who you build credibility with, and hopefully friendships!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-oneself&#34;&gt;For oneself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generally speaking, the more code you write, the better your coding skills so if you want to improve your skills this is an ideal way to do it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the sheer fun of doing cool stuff, especially if you don&amp;#8217;t get to do cool stuff in the day job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To do it &amp;#8220;the way it should be done&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH tunnels on Windows for R</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-03-14-ssh-tunnels-windows-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 13:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-03-14-ssh-tunnels-windows-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;#8217;ve had to get to grips with SSH tunnels. SSH tunnels are really useful for maintaining remote network integrity and work in a secure fashion. It is, however, a pain to open PuTTY and log in all the time, mainly because I couldn&amp;#8217;t script it in R! It&amp;#8217;s been a trial, but like most things it turned out to be pretty simple in the end so I thought I&amp;#8217;d share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-8217-s-required&#34;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s required?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html&#34;&gt;PuTTY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://winscp.net/eng/index.php&#34;&gt;winSCP&lt;/a&gt; (optional tool, generally helpful)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware the Microsoft Edge as a PDF reader</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-03-09-beware-the-microsoft-edge-as-a-pdf-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 14:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-03-09-beware-the-microsoft-edge-as-a-pdf-reader/</guid>
      <description>Just a heads-up for people like me who&amp;#8217;ve gotten a Windows 10 machine and have used Edge as a PDF reader. I was too lazy to install Adobe Reader and was instead using Edge as my default reader. This gave me a mini-heart attack when I received a proof for my super cool NFC-tag laptop stickers and the colour was wrong. WTF right, I mean we did send it as CMYK and all that jazz so it should be right, a printer wouldn&amp;#8217;t screw that up, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the Tiny Icons, Big Text issue on my XPS13</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-01-13-fixing-the-tiny-icons-big-text-issue-on-my-xps13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 17:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-01-13-fixing-the-tiny-icons-big-text-issue-on-my-xps13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-issue&#34;&gt;The Issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my Dell XPS13. It&amp;#8217;s fast, sleek and gorgeous. It does however have one little problem: the icon and text size. The text was always too big for the buttons and boxes and the icons were so small you could hardly see them. This made it hard to use my machine without an external screen (which doesn&amp;#8217;t have that issue and should have been my first clue!)&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_61507&#34; style=&#34;width: 2062px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lockedata/image/upload/v1499850515/Example-of-the-text-and-icon-size-issue_x2xtxn.png&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-61507&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-61507 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lockedata/image/upload/v1499850515/Example-of-the-text-and-icon-size-issue_x2xtxn.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example of the text and icon size issue&#34; width=&#34;2062&#34; height=&#34;982&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;An example of the issue I was dealing with&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bride of Frankenstein: TFS &#43; R</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-03-20-bride-of-frankenstein-tfs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 10:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-03-20-bride-of-frankenstein-tfs-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The unholy abomination of trying to use TFS as my central repository for my R code over the past year has been tough and you may or not be looking at the screen as if I&amp;#8217;m a crazy fool for even trying. Of course, now I have good news, because I&amp;#8217;ve broken the back of the main issue I had with TFS. The crucial link was being able to programatically create Git repositories within a single project for small projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the API, I&amp;#8217;ve been able to write an &lt;a title=&#34;tfsR&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/stephlocke/tfsR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R package&lt;/a&gt; with functions that now save me at least 15 minutes of time and effort each time I want a new project. So I can happily holler &amp;#8220;IT&amp;#8217;S ALIVE!!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spell check your spreadsheets</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-20-spell-check-spreadsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 10:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-20-spell-check-spreadsheets/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick tip for spreadsheet users about spellchecking in Excel.
Firstly, yes you can spell check a spreadsheet.
Secondly, you do it either by going to Review &amp;gt; Check Spelling, or more easily by hitting F7 on your keyboard.
Please, please spellcheck your work &amp;#8211; it makes your work much more professional and saves you having to do it manually!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photoshop image macro (or something even better!)</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-13-photoshop-image-macro-something-even-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 10:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-13-photoshop-image-macro-something-even-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time in Photoshop for someone in BI. Between cleaning up images, building logos for my latest project, or producing material for user groups, I probably use it at least once a week. Through it all, I usually need to produce variants, in different file formats and sizes. So it can quickly become a dozen uses of the Save As&amp;#8230; or Save for Web functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate manual work, so you can see why it was frustrating in the extreme. Then I realised how silly I was being by not having already googled for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while because my keyword searches weren&amp;#8217;t the terms Photoshop use but I found the Secret Sauce. And if you&amp;#8217;re the sort of person who&amp;#8217;d type &amp;#8220;photoshop image macro&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; here&amp;#8217;s how you do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated site</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-03-updated-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 16:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2015-01-03-updated-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;#8217;ve been using this blog more recently, the page speed has been becoming much more frustrating. So today, I&amp;#8217;ve done some stuff to improve it and it&amp;#8217;s now twice as fast as it used to be. Please let me know what you think of the new style!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for database and Excel people</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-09-15-r-for-database-and-excel-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 18:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-09-15-r-for-database-and-excel-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-r&#34;&gt;What is R?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R is a statistical language for doing all sorts of analytics based on many different types of data and it&amp;#8217;s also an open source platform that allows people to extend the base functionality.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r-project.org/about.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More details&lt;/a&gt; are available from the horse&amp;#8217;s mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-i-give-it-a-go&#34;&gt;How can I give it a go?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/ide/download/desktop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt; an awesome development environment for R.  There is also an excellent online &lt;a href=&#34;http://tryr.codeschool.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R learning site&lt;/a&gt;.  I do not recommend sticking with just R &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;re used to a lot more convenience and good development bits and bobs like IntelliSense and Rstudio really delivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tired of right-clicking on folders and going to properties to get the folder size?</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-09-07-tired-of-right-clicking-on-folders-and-going-to-properties-to-get-the-folder-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-09-07-tired-of-right-clicking-on-folders-and-going-to-properties-to-get-the-folder-size/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-dt&#34;&gt;
  It&amp;#8217;s a nightmare when I&amp;#8217;m trying to find out what&amp;#8217;s clogging up my hard drive, particularly now that I have an SSD and can no longer be quite so lazy and sprawling with myriad files and downloads.  This is the case even after moving most contents to Dropbox and putting this on my slow 1Tb harddrive. It can get really tiresome to be running out of space and having to trawl through, right-clicking on different folders.  It was boring but it was how you did it, well now I am enlightened, and now I don&amp;#8217;t have to pour my time down the drain.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-dt&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic named range generator</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-08-27-dynamic-named-range-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 21:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-08-27-dynamic-named-range-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do I use &lt;a title=&#34;Dynamic named ranges – the basics&#34; href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/dynamic-named-ranges-the-basics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dynamic named ranges&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I work, most reports are exposed via a web front-end and Excel can create an external connection and retrieve the information.&amp;nbsp; This is much safer than using direct database connections in workbooks.&amp;nbsp; A problem with web queries though is that they cannot be converted to Tables in order for referencing columns and the dataset as a whole to be made easier.&amp;nbsp; As a result, dynamic named ranges are a necessity for producing easy to develop and manage spreadsheets since the volumes in the raw data can change over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I save myself time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A raw data table with 20 columns will take a long time to create the named ranges for, given that I want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dynamic range covering the headers too for pivot tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dynamic range without headers for vlookups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dynamic range for each column without headers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a macro, assigned to a nice button on my ribbon, to generate all the relevant ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the special considerations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Structure &amp;#8211; raw data tables should ALWAYS be set up in a specific way &amp;#8211; with the Primary Key on the left hand side and always filled in, with no empty rows or columns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special characters &amp;#8211; range names can&amp;#8217;t contain special characters.&amp;nbsp; The VBA uses the &lt;a title=&#34;RegEx functions in VBA&#34; href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/regex-functions-in-vba/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RegEx&lt;/a&gt; functionality to strip these out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numbers &amp;#8211; range names can&amp;#8217;t have numbers either.&amp;nbsp; We can&amp;#8217;t just strip out the numbers like we would special characters because they might be important like Grade1, Grade2 and Grade3 and collapsing them all to the name Grade would be a problem.&amp;nbsp; Instead, the macro converts all numbers to the corresponding letter in the alphabet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much the data will grow?&amp;nbsp; By default I set the macro to use 10 times the number of records present when I run the macro &amp;#8211; if it&amp;#8217;s already bigger than 25k rows, the number will need to be reduced, and if I don&amp;#8217;t think 10 times the number will be adequate, I&amp;#8217;ll increase the number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RegEx functions in VBA</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-08-20-regex-functions-in-vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 18:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-08-20-regex-functions-in-vba/</guid>
      <description>Regular Expressions (RegEx) is a common string processing technique for handling strings that conform to patterns, as opposed to fixed strings.XKCD Perl Problems
It is an excellent set of functionality that is available in most programming languages, and even in SQL. It is however not readily available in Excel or VBA. This has it downsides if you&amp;#8217;re trying to complex string matching and extraction, so in my personal workbook, I include the RegEx functions available at http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic named ranges – the basics</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-07-27-dynamic-named-ranges-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 19:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-07-27-dynamic-named-ranges-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>Whoah nelly, what&amp;#8217;s a named range first of all let alone a dynamic one?
A named range is a shorthand or alias for a set of cells in Excel. These can be created easily by simply selecting one or more cells and using the name box to give it whatever name you feel relevant. This alias can then be used in formula to make something much more insightful like =A1_VAT as opposed to =A1_0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Platformer</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-06-28-my-first-platformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 22:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-06-28-my-first-platformer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-platformer&#34;&gt;My Platformer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s my first attempt at a platformer, built in Construct 2 and using sprites form Game Maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #99cc00;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Day/Night Cycle Demo</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-06-27-my-daynight-cycle-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 20:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-06-27-my-daynight-cycle-demo/</guid>
      <description>My Day/Night Cycle Here&amp;#8217;s my Day/Night cycle function demo, built in Construct 2. (Time moving at 4 minutes per second)
It took me a day and a half of hair pulling, but I&amp;#8217;ve only been using Construct 2 for a week so I suppose it&amp;#8217;s not too shabby. It uses only 6 events, 2 global variables and 9 objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making charts with conditionally coloured series</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-25-making-charts-with-conditionally-coloured-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 16:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-25-making-charts-with-conditionally-coloured-series/</guid>
      <description>The example I&amp;#8217;m running through is available at http://sdrv.ms/11lH3KR
&amp;nbsp;
The scenario we&amp;#8217;re looking at is where we want to be able to convey quality within a chart by having differently coloured columns, based on different conditions that we want to specify. Unfortunately, the ability to natively apply conditional formatting isn&amp;#8217;t yet present, but we can mimic it by overlaying series of the same size that are coloured differently.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Center across selection</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-24-center-across-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 15:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-24-center-across-selection/</guid>
      <description>Merging cells is easily done and can help make a spreadsheet look neat, but what you really, really should be doing instead is centering across the selection so it looks merged but isn&amp;#8217;t. Center across selection though is hidden away and therefore time-consuming to use &amp;#8211; no wonder people have bad habits! I wanted to do things the better way, but was lazy, so in the end I made a macro to go in my personal workbook and assigned it to my ribbon (I do this a lot).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to go home…</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-19-time-to-go-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 15:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-19-time-to-go-home/</guid>
      <description>I do a lot of work in spreadsheets and some cannot be left open on my PC as that&amp;#8217;d make them locked for the morning report refresh. After a bunch of times having to buy cakes for so delaying the reports, I put something in place to stop it. It also had the very nice side effect of telling me to go home.
The first thing to do is make sure you have a personal workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectless Check Boxes using VBA</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-12-objectless-chec-boxes-using-vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 14:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-12-objectless-chec-boxes-using-vba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my first ever blog post (be gentle with me!) I wanted to talk about an issue I have with Excel’s check box object, and my way of resolving it. It’s not perfect, and I’d love to hear of any other versions or ideas you may have. So here&amp;#8217;s how I create check boxes in Excel without using Excel check boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-with-check-box-objects&#34;&gt;The Problem with Check Box Objects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They look good and they work well, there’s no denying they do what they’re supposed to, but they also annoy the heck out of me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;list-style-type: circle;&#34;&gt;
  As far as I’ve been able to find they can’t be properly bound to a cell; this means if you want to get rid of them you need to select them and delete them, which can be a big job
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;list-style-type: circle;&#34;&gt;
  If you want to refer to their state in simple terms you need to add a linked cell and refer to that, which to me is just plain messy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;list-style-type: circle;&#34;&gt;
  They’re awkward to format and style and if you want a big tick you need a big box and as such you need a big cell… again, messy
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #99cc00;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WordPress on Azure</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-11-setting-up-wordpress-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 22:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2013-05-11-setting-up-wordpress-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog was configured super rapidly with goDaddy and Azure, instead of my previous implementation on EC2.  I&amp;#8217;ve forgone the multi-site installation, with attendant subdomains, and gone for a straight wordpress Website (one of the Azure features).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had an Azure account I&amp;#8217;d gone through the billing setup for &amp;#8211; but that was really simple anyway, so getting the blog up and running consisted of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>