<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community workshops</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/community-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/community-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Following on from when we announced the availability of our community workshops, we&amp;#8217;ve got three in the next three months that folks can attend.
May 19th &amp;#8211; Data science project in a day We&amp;#8217;ll be in Kiev, Ukraine, doing a whole data science project in a day. This is intended to give people a little bit of code, process, and critical thinking along the whole data science workflow. This will enable folks to see how it hangs together and decide where and how much they want to invest their learning in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of the Beards: access it online</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/battle-of-the-beards-access-it-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 11:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/battle-of-the-beards-access-it-online/</guid>
      <description>A fortnight ago I wrote&amp;nbsp;Dear South Wales &amp;amp; Bristol readers: I need your help&amp;nbsp;as Battle of the Beards was failing. Well, we didn&amp;#8217;t manage to make it to the minimum amount of attendees to go forward with it and on Thursday it looked like I was going to have to cancel it.
Then inspiration struck &amp;#8230; the major reasons why maybe people didn&amp;#8217;t want to attend are:
 Too far to travel Hard to get a day off work Not interested in all the talks  What would make it so people didn&amp;#8217;t have to travel, could watch from work, and see only the sessions they&amp;#8217;re interested in?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear South Wales &amp; Bristol readers: I need your help</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/dear-south-wales--bristol-readers-i-need-your-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 12:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/dear-south-wales--bristol-readers-i-need-your-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battle of the Beards is an annual tech event in Cardiff that&amp;#8217;s previously been an evening affair but is now a day-long conference. We&amp;#8217;re hosting half-hour talks on security, infrastructure, software craftmanship, front-end development, and data visualisation. We&amp;#8217;re starting out the day with bacon baps and it just gets better from there. Tickets cost £15 and there&amp;#8217;s the option to add a donation to the charity we&amp;#8217;re supporting with the event, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecalmzone.net/&#34;&gt;Campaign Against Living Miserably&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now ticket sales are really low and without your help, we&amp;#8217;ll have to cancel the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m hoping you can help make this event succeed by doing one or both of two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://battleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&#34;&gt;register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; if it&amp;#8217;s of interest to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recommend it to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[button text=&amp;#8221;REGISTER&amp;#8221; color=&amp;#8221;orange&amp;#8221; link=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://battleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&#34;&gt;https://battleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;] [button text=&amp;#8221;TWEET&amp;#8221; color=&amp;#8221;blue&amp;#8221; link=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Hey%20%23tweeps%20-%20%23battleofthebeards%20is%20on%20March%2029th%20in%20Cardiff.%20You%20should%20check%20it%20out!%0Abattleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/home?status=Hey%20%23tweeps%20-%20%23battleofthebeards%20is%20on%20March%2029th%20in%20Cardiff.%20You%20should%20check%20it%20out!%0Abattleofthebeards.eventbrite.co.uk&amp;amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Data and Docker</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/talking-data-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/talking-data-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>If you need to know about persisting data in the world of containers then I recently did a talk and a spot on a podcast that should help you out. My NDC London talk Data + Docker = Disconbobulating? cover the basics and architectural decisions. In my podcast spot Data and Docker on .Net Rocks we go into more depth about the architectural decisions facing you when working with data and Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first MVP Summit – a fantastic reminder</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/my-first-mvp-summit--a-fantastic-reminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 10:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/my-first-mvp-summit--a-fantastic-reminder/</guid>
      <description>I had the tremendous pleasure of going to the Microsoft MVP Summit this week and it was a fantastic experience. It also taught me a valuable lesson &amp;#8211; I need to be an attendee more.
Microsoft award ~4,000 people their Most Valued Professional (MVP) award each year. MVPs are influential, helpful people who work with Microsoft services. I&amp;#8217;m not sure what I did to get in when so many awesome folks I know haven&amp;#8217;t but I&amp;#8217;m very proud to be in receipt of the Award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note to (potential) new speakers: It’s ok not to be perfect!</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/a-note-to-potential-new-speakers-its-ok-not-to-be-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 10:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/a-note-to-potential-new-speakers-its-ok-not-to-be-perfect/</guid>
      <description>This is a T-SQL Tuesday Post in response to Andy Bek&amp;#8217;s kick off about growing new speakers. You can write your own advice for new speakers, or blog your journey to speaking.
 I&amp;#8217;m always trying to encourage new speakers and the biggest fear I hear is &amp;#8220;I won&amp;#8217;t be any good at it&amp;#8221;. Well, you won&amp;#8217;t be perfect at it, that&amp;#8217;s for sure. You may start off really bad at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections: SQL Relay is coming</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/reflections-sql-relay-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 08:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/reflections-sql-relay-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty quiet recently, I haven&amp;#8217;t presented much, I haven&amp;#8217;t blogged much, I haven&amp;#8217;t worked on my open source projects much. All my energy left over from my major work project has been going into SQL Relay. SQL Relay is an ambitious project every year. We organise a conference that goes on tour. In previous years, I&amp;#8217;ve gone to 8 cities over two weeks. Over the past 4 years, I&amp;#8217;ve been part of organising 30 conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsoring community events (SCE)</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/sponsoring-community-events-sce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/sponsoring-community-events-sce/</guid>
      <description>Sponsoring community events &amp;#8211; is it right for you? This series of posts will take you through the things you need to know to help you decide.
Over the coming weeks, this new series will go through the in&amp;#8217;s and out&amp;#8217;s of sponsoring community events. Community events are fantastic from an attendee perspective, but when you&amp;#8217;re handing over cash you need to know what you&amp;#8217;re letting yourself in for and how you get return on investment (ROI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for (lightning) talks</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/ideas-for-lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/ideas-for-lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m trying to encourage more lightning talks at my user groups, and I started by writing a plea to folks at my local R user group, caRdiff. In it I included some ideas for lightning talks, and of course, these can be used as the basis for long talks too. We had some fun batting this list around and expanding it in the Cardiff dev group. I thought it was worth sharing, and getting some more ideas from you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad ways to run a user group</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/bad-ways-to-run-a-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 12:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/bad-ways-to-run-a-user-group/</guid>
      <description>I love user groups and I always want there to be more. I&amp;#8217;m not a perfect organiser but I run reasonable groups. When I see organisers doing it badly, it makes me sad. There&amp;#8217;s lots of great ways to run a user group, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d cover some of the bad ways to run a user group. The anti-patterns if you will 😀
Don&amp;#8217;t advertise Your group isn&amp;#8217;t on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PASS #Summit2016 submissions feedback</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/my-pass-#summit2016-submissions-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 11:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/my-pass-#summit2016-submissions-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really liked the way Brent showed us &lt;a href=&#34;https://ozar.me/2016/06/feedback-on-my-sqlpass-summit16-abstract-submissions/&#34;&gt;his feedback received&lt;/a&gt; and since mimicry is the best form of flattery, I thought I&amp;#8217;d go ahead and do it too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t get any accepted abstracts, and I&amp;#8217;m actually grateful. The recent stresses to do with the PASS dramas aside, I would have had to use 5 days holiday time, pay for flights and hotel, and then flown out a week later for MVP Summit. Now I can attend some other conferences and/or have a Christmas break! Woo hoo 😀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent presentations</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/recent-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/recent-presentations/</guid>
      <description>The last month or so has been a whirlwind of awesomeness with a veritable bevvy of user group and conference talks on my part! I thought I would share the materials with you and provide some brief thoughts on how each presentation went.
Sessions  SQL Saturday Exeter : Stats 101 London Business Analytics (LBAG) : Skilling up to code with data SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : Cut the R Learning Curve SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : R in the Microsoft Data Platform (full day of training) IT Pro Portugal : Being lazy with infrastructure  SQL Saturday Exeter My presentation, in my opinion, was exceedingly brave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#satRdays voting closes May 31st</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/#satrdays-voting-closes-may-31st/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 12:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/#satrdays-voting-closes-may-31st/</guid>
      <description>Voting for 2 of the 3 locations for satRday conferences will be closing at the end of May 31st (GMT). It&amp;#8217;s been a phenomenal turnout with more than 1,500 votes so far.
You can still vote if you haven&amp;#8217;t already!
EU status Budapest, Hungary, is where Gergely will be throwing the EU event and it&amp;#8217;s tentatively set for September.
US status Chicago started out with a close runner of Washington DC, but that all changed as folks realised they could visit Puerto Rico and get fantastic learning, or Puerto Rico has for more R people than my tenuous grasp of geography led me to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRday location voting now open</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/satrday-location-voting-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 15:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/satrday-location-voting-now-open/</guid>
      <description>satRdays, free R conferences, are a project being supported by the R Consortium. When Gergely and I submitted our proposal, we said we&amp;#8217;d be supporting three conferences:
 Budapest, Hungary (Gergely&amp;#8217;s home turf) Somewhere in the US Somewhere else in the world  We&amp;#8217;ve had an overwhelming response with 40 submitted conferences but for the fully-funded ones, there can only be three. We are looking at how the runners up can do the next wave of events but we want to get the ball rolling on the first three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRdays are go!</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/satrdays-are-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 13:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/satrdays-are-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m very pleased to say that the R Consortium agreed to the support the satRday project!
The idea kicked off in November and I was over the moon with the response from the community, then we garnered support before submitting to the Consortium and I must have looped the moon a few times as we had more than 500 responses. Now the R Consortium are supporting us and we can turn all that enthusiasm into action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming R for Microsoft training days</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/upcoming-r-for-microsoft-training-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 09:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/upcoming-r-for-microsoft-training-days/</guid>
      <description>In May, I will be delivering two R for Microsoft training days. These two days will focus on some R fundamentals and applying these fundamentals within the Microsoft Data Platform. These training days are ideal if you know one half of the components &amp;#8211; whether that&amp;#8217;s the R bit or the Microsoft BI bit. Either way, you&amp;#8217;ll learn about the other half.
SQLBits SQLBits XV is being held in Liverpool this year and my training day is on May 4th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRdays: final push</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/satrdays-final-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/satrdays-final-push/</guid>
      <description>I talked back in November about the idea of an RSaturday, which were free community-driven conferences on R. Since then, we created a GitHub repository and started hammering out the details for satRdays. The current proposal consists of:
 A name: satRday A proposition: Free/cheap (&amp;lt;£30) conferences organised by user groups around the world. Attendees get more access to training in R, with a much lower cost-barrier. We develop more speakers on R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should presenters have to pay to attend?</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/should-presenters-have-to-pay-to-attend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/should-presenters-have-to-pay-to-attend/</guid>
      <description>I recently did something for the first time: I declined to speak somewhere. It was never stated on the submission page, and was raised only after my session was accepted &amp;#8211; they wanted me to buy a ticket to attend and I refused&amp;nbsp;to do that.
As a speaker I love donating my time and I really don&amp;#8217;t mind paying my own&amp;nbsp;Travel and Expenses (T&amp;amp;E) but to have to pay to get in the door of the place I&amp;#8217;m speaking at feels wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturdays but for R?</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/sqlsaturdays-but-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 19:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/sqlsaturdays-but-for-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: Proposal now being developed after fantastic community support. Check out satRdays on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stephlocke/RSaturday-proposal&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and contribute your opinions!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a contact from a very nice chap in Dallas a month ago about whether in the R world we do anything like SQLSaturdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about the SQLSaturdays he said was not that they&amp;#8217;re free (well it helps!) but that they&amp;#8217;re on his time. Developing his skills was something he couldn&amp;#8217;t get signed off by his boss so he wanted to be able to do it by himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In answer to the question of whether there are local(ish) weekend conferences happening regularly for R, my answer was &amp;#8220;not really&amp;#8221; and it&amp;#8217;s a shame because the R community is fantastic. I started thinking about why we don&amp;#8217;t have them and what would be needed to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free / cheap regional small-medium conferences are a must for growing user knowledge and speakers in R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some recent posts over on the Mango blog</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/some-recent-posts-over-on-the-mango-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 17:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/some-recent-posts-over-on-the-mango-blog/</guid>
      <description>Since August, I&amp;#8217;ve had the pleasure to work at Mango Solutions, a data science consultancy, as a Principal Consultant.
In that time, I&amp;#8217;ve been to EARL London, SQL Relay, and SQL in the City, so conference season has been in full swing with more to come in the form EARL Boston next week. Surprisingly, I&amp;#8217;ve also found some time to help some customers out and write some blog posts over on the Mango site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps – it’s a thing (honest)</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/dataops--its-a-thing-honest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 20:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/dataops--its-a-thing-honest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I presented a &lt;a href=&#34;https://1drv.ms/p/s!AiZm2P6YHtSfjye0xDn_fuL80eSp&#34;&gt;lightning talk on DataOps&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlinthecity.red-gate.com/london-2015/&#34;&gt;SQL in the City&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic day and a great opportunity to catch up with how the database side of things is evolving to embrace &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DevOps&#34;&gt;DevOps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lightning talk was titled &lt;em&gt;DataOps &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s a thing (honest)&lt;/em&gt; and focused on what is essentially DevOps ported out of the developer sphere and into the data professional sphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Relay is here!</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/sql-relay-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 09:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/sql-relay-is-here/</guid>
      <description>SQL Relay is back on tour! Our 6th event sees us yet again touring the country bringing awesome speakers to eight cities over 2 weeks.
As usual we&amp;#8217;re improving things:
 A new platform called Attendee.Events which allows easier registration &amp;amp; speaker submission A whole bunch of webinars planned to get in the swing of things More breadth &amp;#8211; this year each event includes a dedicated track to R, machine learning etc, on top of SQL Server and business intelligence More content &amp;#8211; instead of swapping out existing slots for breadth, we added more tracks A green initiative &amp;#8230; see it on the day Improved speaker experience &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;re building on last year&amp;#8217;s fun bus with the help of SQL Sentry to make it easier and more fun for speakers to do multiple events, as well as offering first timers some mentoring as most of the organisers are also speakers  You&amp;#8217;ll see a lot of announcements about Relay over the next few months, but I hope this little post inspires you to check out our events 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R training day mk2 – @SQLSatMcr</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/r-training-day-mk2--sqlsatmcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 08:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/r-training-day-mk2--sqlsatmcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in April, for SQL Saturday Exeter I ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/&#34;&gt;my first ever full day of training&lt;/a&gt;. Next month sees me taking my second tilt at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sign up for my R training day, July 24th, in Manchester you can go to the pre-con homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I may say so myself, it&amp;#8217;s a steal at £99 but then they all are! For instance, Andrew Fryer&amp;#8217;s training day covers the Machine Learning use of R via Azure, so if you&amp;#8217;re already wrangling numbers like a pro in R, understanding how you can apply it to snazzy webservices is a great way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many is too many conferences?</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/how-many-is-too-many-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 17:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/how-many-is-too-many-conferences/</guid>
      <description>The SQL Server community has a lot of events. In the UK alone this year we will have/had in 2015:
 more than 75 user group meetings 5 SQL Saturdays 8 days of Relay 1 SQL in the City 3 to 5 days of SQLBits possibly a SQL Santa and probably more that I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten or not know about at the time of writing this  You could attend 2 days of conference per month (cpm from now on) on average in the UK alone, just at dedicated SQL events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Portugal</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/sqlsaturday-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 09:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/sqlsaturday-portugal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlsaturday.com/369/EventHome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Portugal 2015&lt;/a&gt; has been a huge amount of fun but I&amp;#8217;ve also learnt a lot. A big thank you to the organisers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are my slides and notes from sessions I attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-bi&#34;&gt;Agile BI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My session slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Saturday Exeter: Steph &amp; Oz’s slides</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/sql-saturday-exeter-steph--ozs-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 16:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/sql-saturday-exeter-steph--ozs-slides/</guid>
      <description>Well SQL Saturday Exeter flew by. T&amp;#8217;was great catching up with people, seeing folks learn how to use (old &amp;amp; new) tools better, and just generally watching everyone having a great time at one of the best organised conferences I have the pleasure of going to.
Here are links to all the slide decks etc that we presented this weekend:
 My R: analysis to integration training day notes &amp;amp; source code My agile BI slide deck My Shiny: dashboards in R slide deck &amp;amp; source code Oz&amp;#8217;s SSRS: Beyond the basics slide deck &amp;amp; source code  If you attended any of our sessions, give us some constructive criticism!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming social anxiety to attend user groups</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/overcoming-social-anxiety-to-attend-user-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 14:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/overcoming-social-anxiety-to-attend-user-groups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some people it might sound silly, but a frequent reason why people don&amp;#8217;t sign up or don&amp;#8217;t make it to their local user group is to do with social anxiety. I totally understand this &amp;#8211; a room full of people you don&amp;#8217;t know can be a daunting experience. I still get nervous when attending a new user group for the first time and I run three user groups, and speak at user groups and conferences all round the country!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post takes you through the worries, and explains how I&amp;#8217;ve approached some of the issues. Hopefully, this&amp;#8217;ll help you get more people in to your local user group and learning, whether it&amp;#8217;s because you have the tools to help yourself, or understand and can help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A busy month or so</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/a-busy-month-or-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/a-busy-month-or-so/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m really looking forward to a few months of user group and conference awesomeness:
 Feb 24: CaRdiff presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Feb 26: Oxford UG presenting Learning the ropes via the community Mar 4-6: Helping out at SQLBits Mar 7: SQLBits presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Mar 9: SQL Cardiff with Jen &amp;amp; Sean McCown presenting Mar 17: Diff.Net with Scott Hanselman presenting Mar 31: SQL Cardiff with the Battle of the Beards  Then even more fun kicks in with a SQLSaturday Exeter precon, a visit to unified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My R Pre-Con: SQLSat Exeter</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/my-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 10:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/my-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I covered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my post on SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m going to be doing a full day of R training on &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;April 24th&lt;/a&gt; that takes you from cabin boy to first mate in a day. You can&amp;#8217;t be captain because I&amp;#8217;m Captain&amp;#8230; until you go back to your own ship&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; you can be captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attend my day of training about R if you&amp;#8217;d like to learn R, best practices, and how to manage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s £150 (early bird) and can be booked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&amp;#8217;s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Exeter 2015</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! The kind and crazy folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/372/eventhome.aspx&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015 homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt; accepted my submitted training day for their roster. Before I wax lyrical on the virtues of being locked in a room with me all day, I thought I&amp;#8217;d better cover the fundamentals of the event itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the awesome video&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>