<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaking on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speaking on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 10:42:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/blog/tags/speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A note to (potential) new speakers: It’s ok not to be perfect!</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-11-08-note-potential-new-speakers-ok-not-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 10:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-11-08-note-potential-new-speakers-ok-not-perfect/</guid>
      <description>This is a T-SQL Tuesday Post in response to Andy Bek&amp;#8217;s kick off about growing new speakers. You can write your own advice for new speakers, or blog your journey to speaking.
 I&amp;#8217;m always trying to encourage new speakers and the biggest fear I hear is &amp;#8220;I won&amp;#8217;t be any good at it&amp;#8221;. Well, you won&amp;#8217;t be perfect at it, that&amp;#8217;s for sure. You may start off really bad at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for (lightning) talks</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-07-12-ideas-lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-07-12-ideas-lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m trying to encourage more lightning talks at my user groups, and I started by writing a plea to folks at my local R user group, caRdiff. In it I included some ideas for lightning talks, and of course, these can be used as the basis for long talks too. We had some fun batting this list around and expanding it in the Cardiff dev group. I thought it was worth sharing, and getting some more ideas from you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PASS #Summit2016 submissions feedback</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-06-23-pass-summit-2016-submissions-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 11:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-06-23-pass-summit-2016-submissions-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really liked the way Brent showed us &lt;a href=&#34;https://ozar.me/2016/06/feedback-on-my-sqlpass-summit16-abstract-submissions/&#34;&gt;his feedback received&lt;/a&gt; and since mimicry is the best form of flattery, I thought I&amp;#8217;d go ahead and do it too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t get any accepted abstracts, and I&amp;#8217;m actually grateful. The recent stresses to do with the PASS dramas aside, I would have had to use 5 days holiday time, pay for flights and hotel, and then flown out a week later for MVP Summit. Now I can attend some other conferences and/or have a Christmas break! Woo hoo 😀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRday location voting now open</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-05-11-satrday-location-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 15:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-05-11-satrday-location-voting/</guid>
      <description>satRdays, free R conferences, are a project being supported by the R Consortium. When Gergely and I submitted our proposal, we said we&amp;#8217;d be supporting three conferences:
 Budapest, Hungary (Gergely&amp;#8217;s home turf) Somewhere in the US Somewhere else in the world  We&amp;#8217;ve had an overwhelming response with 40 submitted conferences but for the fully-funded ones, there can only be three. We are looking at how the runners up can do the next wave of events but we want to get the ball rolling on the first three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRdays: final push</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-01-06-satrdays-final-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2016-01-06-satrdays-final-push/</guid>
      <description>I talked back in November about the idea of an RSaturday, which were free community-driven conferences on R. Since then, we created a GitHub repository and started hammering out the details for satRdays. The current proposal consists of:
 A name: satRday A proposition: Free/cheap (&amp;lt;£30) conferences organised by user groups around the world. Attendees get more access to training in R, with a much lower cost-barrier. We develop more speakers on R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should presenters have to pay to attend?</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-12-07-should-presenters-have-to-pay-to-attend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-12-07-should-presenters-have-to-pay-to-attend/</guid>
      <description>I recently did something for the first time: I declined to speak somewhere. It was never stated on the submission page, and was raised only after my session was accepted &amp;#8211; they wanted me to buy a ticket to attend and I refused&amp;nbsp;to do that.
As a speaker I love donating my time and I really don&amp;#8217;t mind paying my own&amp;nbsp;Travel and Expenses (T&amp;amp;E) but to have to pay to get in the door of the place I&amp;#8217;m speaking at feels wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boris’ presentation agency – 356labs</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-11-11-boris-presentation-agency-356-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 09:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-11-11-boris-presentation-agency-356-labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://borishristov.com/&#34;&gt;Boris Hristrov&lt;/a&gt;, Data Platform MVP, design whizz, and all-round great guy, recently launched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.356labs.com/&#34;&gt;356labs&lt;/a&gt;. Boris wrote a great &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluralsight.com/courses/presentation-design-introduction&#34;&gt;Presentation Design course&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://preview.pluralsight.com/&#34;&gt;PluralSight&lt;/a&gt;, you can sign up for a trial of PluralSight and watch the course if you&amp;#8217;d like to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an avid reader of design stuff I did find I knew some of the things on the course, but the context and application were very helpful. Off the back of his course, I went on to produce my most visually impressive presentation slide deck to date &amp;#8211; Agile BI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look over his site and asked a few questions since I was really curious. Here are the responses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women doing technology</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-10-24-women-doing-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-10-24-women-doing-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, another Women in Technology conference got forwarded around and looking at the agenda, I snapped. I asked to not see any more goddamn WiT conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really fed up with women talking about being in tech. I don&amp;#8217;t perceive any value in attending a conference dedicated to that. I want to see more women talking about doing tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Relay is here!</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-07-16-sql-relay-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 09:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-07-16-sql-relay-is-here/</guid>
      <description>SQL Relay is back on tour! Our 6th event sees us yet again touring the country bringing awesome speakers to eight cities over 2 weeks.
As usual we&amp;#8217;re improving things:
 A new platform called Attendee.Events which allows easier registration &amp;amp; speaker submission A whole bunch of webinars planned to get in the swing of things More breadth &amp;#8211; this year each event includes a dedicated track to R, machine learning etc, on top of SQL Server and business intelligence More content &amp;#8211; instead of swapping out existing slots for breadth, we added more tracks A green initiative &amp;#8230; see it on the day Improved speaker experience &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;re building on last year&amp;#8217;s fun bus with the help of SQL Sentry to make it easier and more fun for speakers to do multiple events, as well as offering first timers some mentoring as most of the organisers are also speakers  You&amp;#8217;ll see a lot of announcements about Relay over the next few months, but I hope this little post inspires you to check out our events 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Saturday Exeter: Steph &amp; Oz’s slides</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-04-26-sql-saturday-exeter-steph-ozs-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 16:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-04-26-sql-saturday-exeter-steph-ozs-slides/</guid>
      <description>Well SQL Saturday Exeter flew by. T&amp;#8217;was great catching up with people, seeing folks learn how to use (old &amp;amp; new) tools better, and just generally watching everyone having a great time at one of the best organised conferences I have the pleasure of going to.
Here are links to all the slide decks etc that we presented this weekend:
 My R: analysis to integration training day notes &amp;amp; source code My agile BI slide deck My Shiny: dashboards in R slide deck &amp;amp; source code Oz&amp;#8217;s SSRS: Beyond the basics slide deck &amp;amp; source code  If you attended any of our sessions, give us some constructive criticism!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A busy month or so</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-11-busy-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-02-11-busy-month/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m really looking forward to a few months of user group and conference awesomeness:
 Feb 24: CaRdiff presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Feb 26: Oxford UG presenting Learning the ropes via the community Mar 4-6: Helping out at SQLBits Mar 7: SQLBits presenting Shiny: Dashboards in R Mar 9: SQL Cardiff with Jen &amp;amp; Sean McCown presenting Mar 17: Diff.Net with Scott Hanselman presenting Mar 31: SQL Cardiff with the Battle of the Beards  Then even more fun kicks in with a SQLSaturday Exeter precon, a visit to unified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My R Pre-Con: SQLSat Exeter</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-24-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 10:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-24-r-pre-con-sqlsat-exeter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I covered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my post on SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m going to be doing a full day of R training on &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;April 24th&lt;/a&gt; that takes you from cabin boy to first mate in a day. You can&amp;#8217;t be captain because I&amp;#8217;m Captain&amp;#8230; until you go back to your own ship&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; you can be captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attend my day of training about R if you&amp;#8217;d like to learn R, best practices, and how to manage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s £150 (early bird) and can be booked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sqlsatexeter.azurewebsites.net/?page_id=342&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter, Steph Locke Pre-con details&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&amp;#8217;s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Intro to R case study</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-21-organised-speaking-intro-r-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 09:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-21-organised-speaking-intro-r-case-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/organised-speaking-iterative-development/&#34; title=&#34;Organised speaking – presentation design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iterative presentation design post&lt;/a&gt; I promised a case study. I thought I&amp;#8217;d cover my most presented session &lt;em&gt;Intro to R&lt;/em&gt;, in future called &lt;em&gt;Knowing your Rs from your elbow&lt;/em&gt; courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/fatherjack&#34; title=&#34;Father Jack&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@FatherJack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history&#34;&gt;A brief history&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I&amp;#8217;ve been using R for the past couple of years and spent the first months struggling with it, I wanted to give a presentation that I would have wanted to see at the beginning. Not one about random bagging and a bunch of other stats but what are the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; ways to do the fundamentals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting to my database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;performing data manipulations, summaries and updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;charting my data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;producing reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few packages cover these awesomely and are much better than base R so whilst I was tackling a massive stats project, the things which took the time and stress were things I could have avoided with ease!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my intro to R, takes people through the things I wish I&amp;#8217;d been taken through thus making those first few months of R pleasant, happy times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Exeter 2015</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-19-sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-19-sqlsaturday-exeter-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! The kind and crazy folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/372/eventhome.aspx&#34; title=&#34;SQLSaturday Exeter 2015 homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Exeter&lt;/a&gt; accepted my submitted training day for their roster. Before I wax lyrical on the virtues of being locked in a room with me all day, I thought I&amp;#8217;d better cover the fundamentals of the event itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the awesome video&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – presentation design</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-18-organised-speaking-iterative-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-18-organised-speaking-iterative-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to outline my approach to presentation design, or development as I prefer to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I consider it development? Well, it&amp;#8217;s a product that can be manually done &amp;amp; delivered but with the potential to scale to thousands of users, I&amp;#8217;d rather the product be easy to maintain &amp;amp; deploy, deliver real value to the users, and keep up with cutting edge developments in the subject. Also, I call it development because now with the use of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34; title=&#34;Rmarkdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt;, I do actually code my presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-presentation-design&#34;&gt;General presentation design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read and studied a lot about presentations, some of the biggest influences being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Dr. Andrew Abela and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremepresentation.com/&#34; title=&#34;Extreme Presentation Method&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Extreme Presentation Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/buckwoody/&#34; title=&#34;Buck&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buck Woody&lt;/a&gt; and his fantastic presentation style&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2012/04/writing-better-conference-abstracts-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Brent&#39;s blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brent Ozar&lt;/a&gt; and his excellent materials for presentations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Solid fundamentals in presentation training courses (things like INTRO: Intro, Need, Title, Range, Objective)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first come up with the idea for a presentation, I write the abstract for it. In the abstract I set out the tone, material covered, and outline who should attend. This abstract is my requirements doc for later me &amp;#8211; it tells me whether I&amp;#8217;m selling, educating, or entertaining and what I&amp;#8217;m doing it about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, you should always write the abstract first as not only can you write more abstracts than you can presentations but it distills the idea down and helps you think of your audience first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – prioritising events to speak at</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-12-organised-speaking-prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-12-organised-speaking-prioritising-events-to-speak-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my ongoing series about presenting at community events and conferences, I wanted to cover the my personal thought process when it comes to prioritising what events I&amp;#8217;d like to speak at for my goal &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/throw-1-speak-1/&#34; title=&#34;Throw 1, Speak 1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a massive amount of awesome SQL Server and other technology events happening out there. I even throw a SQL Server lunchtime session once a week for the user group! Then of course there&amp;#8217;s all those conferences in the UK and abroad that are worth attending. So how do I event start picking out where I&amp;#8217;d like to talk, and how do I go about getting selected for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – Throw 1, Speak 1</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-08-throw-1-speak-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 10:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-08-throw-1-speak-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following up from my last post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/organised-speaking-session-abstracts/&#34; title=&#34;Organised speaking – session abstracts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;maintaining my session abstracts&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to cover how I&amp;#8217;m doing my scheduling this year for speaking at events. Perhaps more importantly than tech, is the intention and the planning process so I&amp;#8217;ll be covering these factors in more detail than the tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make use of Google services quite a bit, and their &lt;a href=&#34;http://calendar.google.com&#34; title=&#34;Google calendar&#34;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt; system is a great help. So this year I&amp;#8217;ve added a calendar that has all mine (and hopefully Oz&amp;#8217;s) speaking engagements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m then utilising a WordPress plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/gcal-events-list/&#34; title=&#34;Gcal events&#34;&gt;GCal events&lt;/a&gt; to connect to the calendar and pull the info into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/index.php/wheres-steff-oz/&#34; title=&#34;Where’s Steff &amp;amp; Oz?&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;throw-1-speak-1&#34;&gt;Throw 1, Speak 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal this year is to throw one user group event and speak at one event each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organised speaking – session abstracts</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-02-organised-speaking-session-abstracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 09:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/blog/2015-01-02-organised-speaking-session-abstracts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I spoke at 10&amp;nbsp;different events (I think) and was very lucky to be nominated in the Tribal Awards for my Intro to R session. I did just a couple of different session titles and I don&amp;#8217;t think I managed the whole process very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be an easier speaker to deal with, I&amp;#8217;m trying to be more organised so that the selection process of myself &amp;amp; topics is easier whilst also ensuring I don&amp;#8217;t develop too many presentations at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having dealt with awesome serial speakers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://koprowskit.eu/geek/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tobiasz Koprowski&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dcac.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Denny Cherry&lt;/a&gt;, from the organiser end they did a few things which made it much easier to deal with them, particularly given the breadth of topics they can cover!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>