<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 10:02:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Going solo!</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-01-04-going-solo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 10:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2017-01-04-going-solo/</guid>
      <description>The year has started out on a high for me. I&amp;#8217;ve handed in my notice Censornet and I was re-awarded the Data Platform MVP award by Microsoft. I handed in my notice not to go to a new job but to fly solo!
I&amp;#8217;m starting Locke Data in February to help people embed data science skills in their organisations.
Business intelligence has been a thing long enough that there&amp;#8217;s a whole department of people dedicated to it and it generally isn&amp;#8217;t disruptive to other areas of the business and IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ItsALocke.com now with added locks</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-07-itsalocke-com-now-added-locks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 08:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-10-07-itsalocke-com-now-added-locks/</guid>
      <description>This blog now has some extra locks, these are in the URL bar!
It took my fantastic hosters WPEngine a little longer than I would have preferred to get a modern SSL policy. Now that they have, they did it in their typically awesome fashion. You can request a free Let&amp;#8217;s Encrypt SSL certificate from the admin dashboard, and configure how http etc should work in less than 15 minutes, and you don&amp;#8217;t have be a web wizard to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finished my first GameMaker Game</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-09-17-first-gamemaker-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 20:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/2016-09-17-first-gamemaker-game/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with GameMaker, making Asteroids! I mean OK, it&amp;#8217;s just a clone of a classic, but isn&amp;#8217;t that how fledgling artists practice? Initially created following a tutorial, I then went through and added a lot of extra features, including music, splash screens, a pause function and much cleaner code.
Embedding by i-frame is pretty ugly, so please follow the link below to try the game.
Asteroids Game
A/D or Left/Right to turn W or Up to move Space or Right Control to shoot Escape to pause You can download the gmz file, and import into your copy of Game Maker if you&amp;#8217;d like, using this link: https://dl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>