<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordpress on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:00:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itsalocke.com/blog/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy-peasy Q&amp;A bot</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/easy-peasy-qa-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/easy-peasy-qa-bot/</guid>
      <description>Everyone seems to have a live chat option for their site but I&amp;#8217;m frequently away, so I wanted something that people could talk to interactively. This is a perfect scenario for a Q&amp;amp;A bot. Microsoft takes a ton of the pain out of Q&amp;amp;A bots, and it was much easier than I thought to get it added to my WordPress blog. Here is a how to do it for your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An experiment in self-promotion – Revive Old Posts</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/an-experiment-in-self-promotion--revive-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 10:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/an-experiment-in-self-promotion--revive-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been writing (not enough) blog posts for a while now and have built up some neat stuff in the backlog if I may so myself. Alas, a lot of this doesn&amp;#8217;t get seen because it&amp;#8217;s not on the front page or in the top 5 blog posts. Sad that posts like my one on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsalocke.com/anchor-modelling-sixth-normal-form-databases/&#34;&gt;sixth normal form databases&lt;/a&gt; don&amp;#8217;t get enough love, I&amp;#8217;ve installed the WordPress plugin &lt;a href=&#34;https://en-gb.wordpress.org/plugins/tweet-old-post/&#34;&gt;Revive Old Posts&lt;/a&gt; (ROP) to try countering this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 useful CSS sites</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/5-useful-css-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/5-useful-css-sites/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a lot of web development recently, primarily via the magical Hugo platform. Between it and the great themes for it, it&amp;#8217;s making website building fairly painless. Of course, each theme often needs customising to the relevant brand a given site is for. That customising is usually just one by some fonts and by tweaking the CSS.*
I&amp;#8217;ve been relying on some old, and some very new, funky tools to help with CSS hacking and I thought I would share them, in case they should prove useful to you in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photoshop image macro (or something even better!)</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/photoshop-image-macro-or-something-even-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 10:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/photoshop-image-macro-or-something-even-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time in Photoshop for someone in BI. Between cleaning up images, building logos for my latest project, or producing material for user groups, I probably use it at least once a week. Through it all, I usually need to produce variants, in different file formats and sizes. So it can quickly become a dozen uses of the Save As&amp;#8230; or Save for Web functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate manual work, so you can see why it was frustrating in the extreme. Then I realised how silly I was being by not having already googled for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while because my keyword searches weren&amp;#8217;t the terms Photoshop use but I found the Secret Sauce. And if you&amp;#8217;re the sort of person who&amp;#8217;d type &amp;#8220;photoshop image macro&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; here&amp;#8217;s how you do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated site</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/updated-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 16:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/updated-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;#8217;ve been using this blog more recently, the page speed has been becoming much more frustrating. So today, I&amp;#8217;ve done some stuff to improve it and it&amp;#8217;s now twice as fast as it used to be. Please let me know what you think of the new style!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WordPress on Azure</title>
      <link>https://itsalocke.com/blog/setting-up-wordpress-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 22:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsalocke.com/blog/setting-up-wordpress-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog was configured super rapidly with goDaddy and Azure, instead of my previous implementation on EC2.  I&amp;#8217;ve forgone the multi-site installation, with attendant subdomains, and gone for a straight wordpress Website (one of the Azure features).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had an Azure account I&amp;#8217;d gone through the billing setup for &amp;#8211; but that was really simple anyway, so getting the blog up and running consisted of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>