<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Locke Data Blog</title>
    <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Locke Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 08:17:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an R training environment</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/building-an-r-training-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 08:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/building-an-r-training-environment/</guid>
      <description>I recently delivered a day of training at SQLBits and I really upped my game in terms of infrastructure for it. The resultant solution was super smooth and mitigated all the install issues and preparation for attendees. This meant we got to spend the whole day doing R, instead of troubleshooting.
I&amp;#8217;m so happy with the solution for an online R training environment that I want to share the solution, so you can take it and use it for when you need to do training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Data and Docker</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/talking-data-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/talking-data-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>If you need to know about persisting data in the world of containers then I recently did a talk and a spot on a podcast that should help you out. My NDC London talk Data + Docker = Disconbobulating? cover the basics and architectural decisions. In my podcast spot Data and Docker on .Net Rocks we go into more depth about the architectural decisions facing you when working with data and Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent presentations</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/recent-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/recent-presentations/</guid>
      <description>The last month or so has been a whirlwind of awesomeness with a veritable bevvy of user group and conference talks on my part! I thought I would share the materials with you and provide some brief thoughts on how each presentation went.
Sessions  SQL Saturday Exeter : Stats 101 London Business Analytics (LBAG) : Skilling up to code with data SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : Cut the R Learning Curve SQLBits &amp;amp; TUGA : R in the Microsoft Data Platform (full day of training) IT Pro Portugal : Being lazy with infrastructure  SQL Saturday Exeter My presentation, in my opinion, was exceedingly brave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I read this week</title>
      <link>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/stuff-i-read-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 12:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockedata.uk/itsalockeblog/stuff-i-read-this-week/</guid>
      <description> ONS Style guide for writing about statistics  Your coding style can give you away Automated Tinder and the Eigenface R-help mailing list to use cage-fighting to resolve conflicts Application Containers For Cloud Computing Managing Test Data as a Database CI Component &amp;#8211; Part 1 Let the Hackers In: Experts Say Traps Better than Walls How to Write a Blog Post   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>